<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech-and-society on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/tags/tech-and-society/</link><description>Recent content in tech-and-society on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:41:38 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/tags/tech-and-society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software and Politics</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/software-and-politics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:41:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/software-and-politics/</guid><description>Artificacts have Politics https://www.jstor.org/stable/20024652
https://sbuss.substack.com/p/politics-for-software-engineers-part-2 &amp;ldquo;Blockchain voting addresses how to vote in a trust-less society, but a trust-less society cannot have a functioning democracy.&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; error-handling
Potential use of Merkle Trees? (but also, city-is-not-a-tree)
Simplicity is more important that provably correct &amp;ldquo;I think where most software engineers fail at politics, it&amp;rsquo;s in understanding that key point. We tend to over engineer our systems and never need to explain the inner workings to anyone who is non-technical.</description></item><item><title>Fault Tolerance</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</guid><description>Fault Tolerance How do we defend against attacks in distributed systems with no central authority?
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault https://lamport.azurewebsites.net/pubs/byz.pdf
Zooko&amp;rsquo;s Triangle Postulates that names of participants can have at most 2 of these 3 properties
Human-meaningful: Meaningful and memorable (low-entropy) names are provided to the users. Secure: The amount of damage a malicious entity can inflict on the system should be as low as possible. Decentralized: Names correctly resolve to their respective entities without the use of a central authority or service.</description></item><item><title>Creation vs Maintenance</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/creation-vs-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:07:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/creation-vs-maintenance/</guid><description>So much of today&amp;rsquo;s society revolves around creating new things rather than maintaining existing things
Importance of indigenous knowledge and tradition
Do Eastern vs Western cultures have diff takes on this?
https://danluu.com/sounds-easy/ Not just building out an initial system, but also about how maintainable and scalable the system is for the forseable future.
Businesses that actually care about turning a profit will spend a lot of time (hence, a lot of engineers) working on optimizing systems, even if an MVP for the system could have been built in a weekend.</description></item><item><title>Attention Economy</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:27:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</guid><description>attention as a commodity increasingly competitive to compete for everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention
shortening of attention spans? not sure if this is an actual thing &amp;lsquo;digital detox&amp;rsquo; people not just as the products, but as the producers of the product (data) Attention is the main currency of production &amp;ndash; what limits you from doing everything at once. Attention, then, is a common pool resource. It is non-excludable (anyone can bid for their attention) and rivalrous (limited attention).</description></item><item><title>Ephemereal Content</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</guid><description>moving towards live ephemerality pandemic accelerated blending of async and sycn convos video movies vlogs vine/tiktoks text email sms snapchat messages https://honk.me/ Opposite of digital permanence
It is really tempting to cover for mistakes by pretending they never happened. “In Supreme Court opinions, every word matters … When they’re changing the wording of opinions, they’re basically rewriting the law.”
https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2015/10/raiders-of-the-lost-web/409210/
“It’s gone gone.</description></item><item><title>Catch 22</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:28:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</guid><description>If a pilot is deemed insane, they don&amp;rsquo;t have to fly. To be deemed insane, a pilot must request to be evaluated. If a pilot requests to be evaluated, this demonstrates that he must be sane. Therefore, no pilot can ever be deemed insane, and no pilot can get out of flying. paradoxical sitauation -&amp;gt; catch-22
no way to win double bind -&amp;gt; a psychological predicament in which a person receives from a single source conflicting messages that allow no appropriate response to be made</description></item><item><title>Digital Permanence</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</guid><description>Once you share something, you can&amp;rsquo;t unshare it, internet feels intractable
https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/06/the-internet-is-a-collective-hallucination/619320/: &amp;ldquo;Of course, there’s a keenly related problem of permanency for much of what’s online. People communicate in ways that feel ephemeral and let their guard down commensurately, only to find that a Facebook comment can stick around forever. The upshot is the worst of both worlds: Some information sticks around when it shouldn’t, while other information vanishes when it should remain.</description></item><item><title>Labels and Quantization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:22:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Accuracy is more useful in entry-level jobs and for novices, because as skill increases, quantification of skill becomes harder.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;This is because feedback loops which are too short for the overall system makes people focus on inappropriate intermediate goals.&amp;rdquo;
dangers of intermediate proxies? what about in machine learning? using certain quantities for metrics which are just proxies for more difficult to measure qualitative end goals Applicable to feedback-loops &amp;ldquo;Focusing on tight feedback also leads to getting stuck in local maxima.</description></item><item><title>A case for funding Open Source</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/paid-oss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:03:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/paid-oss/</guid><description>Making of Open Source software I’ve recently made my way through Working in Public: The Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software by Nadia Eghbal. Not only does it have some absolutely stunning cover art, it also touches on some thoughts that have been marinating in my head about the intersection of open source and funding. So much so, that I’ve started experiencing the Baader-Meinhof effect, seeing something to do with open source and funding everywhere I look in tweets, conversations, and blogs.</description></item><item><title>Hackathons</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/hackathons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:01:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/hackathons/</guid><description>Full Post -&amp;gt; hackathons
Design Justice hackathons becoming very corporate traces the cooptation of hacker culture by neoliberalism what is neoliberalism -&amp;gt; basically let the market decide everything &amp;ldquo;For example, consider the transformation of agriculture from Indigenous knowledge of small-scale planting, harvesting, and land-management techniques to modern agribusiness with monocultures, pesticides, fertilizers, and roboticized megafarms&amp;rdquo; hackerspaces were described as originally being &amp;ldquo;third spaces&amp;rdquo; outside of the logic of both the communist state and the capitalist market &amp;ldquo;at the same time, without intentional intervention, these spaces find it very difficult to fulfill even their own liberal democratic rhetoric, because they end up dominated by white cis men and by middle-class people with free time and disposable income&amp;rdquo; [hackathons] are understood by corporate managers as potentially effectives ways to identify new talent, and therefore as a possible mechanism in the tech sector hiring pipeline hackathons provide excellent opportunities for the extraction of free labour the assumption that a &amp;ldquo;hackathon for good&amp;rdquo; will be successful if it produces a new app the can help &amp;ldquo;solve a social problem runs deep&amp;rdquo; they nearly always focus on problems and rarely build on existing community assets; and people think hackathons can do things that they usually can&amp;rsquo;t, such as solve big or even little problems, create new products overnight, or &amp;lsquo;level the playing field&amp;rsquo; of innovation through meritocracy urban design and urban planning &amp;ldquo;through such initiatives, city administrators signal that the public is invited to participate in decisionmaking on an ongoing basis, not only at the ballot box every few years&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; in response to city government being more transparent, more administrative data being made available to the public, and administrators actively seeking ideas from engaged publics about how to improve government services and city resident&amp;rsquo;s quality of life neoliberal, technocentric ideas about the city as a machine or as a software system waiting to be optimized have become increasingly prominent citizens should not be reduced to users through the lens of neoliberal governmentality diversity and inclusivity broader availability of digital design and fabrication increases the opportunity for community-controlled design processes that include more diverse users and user stories, with more equitable and inclusive distribution of affordances the assumption that making sites &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; makes them inclusive, without specifically addressing race, class, gender, and/or disability dynamics, is common to many privileged design sites such hackathons [more inclusive hackathons] push hackers to reflect on why they are doing the work they do, push for the ideas and welfare of marginalized communities in the tech sphere, and do so on the terms of their wellbeing and safety for example, this means that it is important to consider food, bio beaks, accessible bathrooms that are friendly to all body types and genders, comfortable spaces to nap or relax, and decent lighting hackathon spaces cultivate a culture that marginalizes hackers with specific needs, including but not limited to women, people with disabilities, people with non-traditional backgrounds, and even individuals with specific dietary restrictions &amp;ldquo;Steer students away from the pitfalls of tech solutionism and technochauvanism&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Make all people good coders, or make all coders good people&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s true that design justice practitioners have to take care that critique does not become our primary activity; an overemphasis on testing, evaluation, and critique can indeed by ultimately disempowering&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;However if resource constraints become an excuse to avoid examining the root of the problem area, then designers will almost always end up, at best, providing Band-Aids for deep wounds and, at worst, actively serving existing power structures&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Frequent critiques of community-controlled design processes include variants of &amp;lsquo;design by committee produces mediocrity&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up with the lowest-common-denominator design!</description></item><item><title>On AI’s ‘Bias Bug’</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 16:27:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</guid><description>This blog post was originally intended to be a TED Talk given at TEDxRedmond but I unfortunately was never accepted. However, I did learn a lot in the process of writing it, and I hope you get some value out of it even its presented through just text.
Hey Google Take a picture in 5 seconds. Say cheese!
See that? This is just one of many examples of where AI is becoming a larger part of what we accept as normal.</description></item></channel></rss>