<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CPSC317 on jzhao.xyz</title>
    <link>https://jzhao.xyz/tags/CPSC317/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CPSC317 on jzhao.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/tags/CPSC317/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Public-key Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Asymmetric-Key-Cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Asymmetric-Key-Cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Asymmetric cryptography involves a pair of keys, one for encrypting (public) another for decrypting (private). One is private ($K^-$), the other is public ($K^+$).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer to peer</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/peer-to-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/peer-to-peer/</guid>
      <description>In contrast to client-server models, peer-to-peer systems are [[thoughts/decentralization|decentralized]] [[thoughts/Network Theory|networks]] with no privileged nodes. Each node performs the same roles as any other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/HTTP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/HTTP/</guid>
      <description>Main method of communication at the Application Layer for the web. A state-transfer protocol.
Connections  Non-persistent HTTP (v1.0)  At most one object is sent over each TCP connection Connection is closed as soon as data is transferred Include an additional round trip for the TCP handshake for each object = $2n$ RTTs where $n$ is number of resources   Persistent HTTP (v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCP</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/TCP/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/TCP/</guid>
      <description>[[thoughts/Transport Layer|Transport layer protocol]]
When a host requires assurance that the remote end has actually received the data it sends. But instead of requesting a signature at the remote end, TCP requires an acknowledgement be returned</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Layer (Networking)</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Application-Layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Application-Layer/</guid>
      <description>Layer 1, the layer above the Transport Layer
Application/Presentation/Session layer
 Unit: Data Responsibilities: human-computer interaction layer, where applications can access the network services (includes [[thoughts/encryption|encryption]], connection, port, and session management)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARP</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ARP/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ARP/</guid>
      <description>Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) Purpose: links the Network Layer (IP address) with the link layer (MAC address)
Case: A wants tot send a datagram to B, but A doesn&amp;rsquo;t know B&amp;rsquo;s MAC address</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHCP</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/DHCP/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/DHCP/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol so they can join a network. Assigns IP addresses to hosts. Main reason was when people started moving devices across networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/DNS/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/DNS/</guid>
      <description>Domain name: an identification string that defines a realm of administrative autonomy, authority, or control within the Internet.
DNS currently has ~300 million DNS registrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IP Addresses</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/IP-Addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/IP-Addresses/</guid>
      <description>IP addresses are 32 bits (4 bytes) split into 4 chunks. Obviously $2^{32}$ is an incredibly large address space so we compress the table using IP prefixes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Layer</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Link-Layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Link-Layer/</guid>
      <description>Layer 4, the layer below the Network Layer and layer above the [[Physical Layer]]
 Hardware Unit: Frame Responsibilities: Routes frames to adjacent machines (“direct” connection).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAT</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/NAT/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/NAT/</guid>
      <description>Network Address Translation Both network and transport layer (violation of abstraction/layering)
 More devices than IP addresses! What do we do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Layer (IP)</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Network-Layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Network-Layer/</guid>
      <description>Layer 3, the layer below the Transport Layer and layer above the Link Layer
 Unit: Packet (datagram) Responsibilities: Routes packet through routers to destination machine (not necessary if two devices are on the same network) Two main functions  Forwarding: move packets from router’s input to appropriate router output (process of getting through a single interchange) Routing: determine route taken by packets from source to destination (process of planning trip from source to destination)    Packet Definition Contains information about the packet itself (metadata) and the body/content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Layer</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Physical-Layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Physical-Layer/</guid>
      <description>Layer 5, layer below the Link Layer
 Hardware Unit: Bits Responsibilities: Encodes data appropriately for the physical medium  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocols</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Protocol/</guid>
      <description>Defines:
 Roles of communicating entities Format of messages Order of messages Actions taken on the transmission, receipt of a message, or other event  Protocols as State Machines A fully-defined protocol must provide a proper action for any event in any state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transport Layer</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Transport-Layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Transport-Layer/</guid>
      <description>Layer 2, the layer below the Application Layer and layer above the Network Layer
 Unit: Segment Responsibilities: Ensures data arrives in order (if required), Recovers lost data (if required), Identifies process on machine, flow control Adds an additional addressing space at the port level (historically a 16 bit uint from 0 to 65535) Can be either be either packet or stream based  Packet - best effort, no established connection, no transport level delay/waiting (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDP</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/UDP/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/UDP/</guid>
      <description>User Datagram Protocol (UDP)  Source Port Destination Port Length Checksum Payload  68 is usually client, 67 is usually server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/VPN/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/VPN/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Private Networks
Motivation:
 Company with multiple locations wants everything to appear as one big network Workers want access to resources restricted to company internal network Users want to bypass regional blocks   VPN Encapsulation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Computing</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/internet-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/internet-computing/</guid>
      <description>Notes for CPSC 317 (see all notes)
The Internet is a network of networks. The main goals was to integrate a number of separately</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/security/</guid>
      <description>Source: Playdough Protocols in Kernel
Integrity of information is critical to relationships of trust as we saw in the episode on game theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
