<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jacky Zhao | Personal Website</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on Jacky Zhao | Personal Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://jzhao.xyz/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/books/</guid><description>Booklist A (mostly) up-to-date archive on some books I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading.
Current Design Justice by Sasha Costanza-Chock Finite and Infinite Games by James P. Carse Mindstorms by Seymour A. Papert 2021 Half of a Yellow Sun by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie 1984 by George Orwell On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous by Ocean Vuong Working in Public: The Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software by Nadia Eghbal When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi Kafka on the Shore by Haruki Murakami The Art of Thinking Clearly by Rolf Dobelli 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari 2020 Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari Measure What Matters by John Doerr A Beautifully Foolish Endeavor by Hank Green The Uninhabitable Earth by David Wallace-Wells The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck by Mark Manson The Death of Ivan Ilyich by Tolstoy</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jzhao.xyz/notwork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/notwork/</guid><description>Not work Contrary to popular belief, I actually have other things I do outside of writing questionable code and school! Here are some things that I&amp;rsquo;m up to nowadays:
Reading There&amp;rsquo;s nothing like cozying up with a cup of hot barley tea on a rainy day with a great book. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently rediscovered the joy of reading thanks to someone very close to me.
Some of my past favourites
When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari A Beautifully Foolish Endeavor by Hank Green Working in Public: The Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software by Nadia Eghbal Full Booklist.</description></item></channel></rss>