<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Newsletters on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/</link><description>Recent content in Newsletters on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:13:01 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:13:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/5/</guid><description>Intro
3 things I’ve found interesting 2 things I’ve been wondering about 1 thing I’ve done Links: https://qualiaspace.substack.com/p/the-future-of-social-media-is-pseudonymous</description></item><item><title>The bookstore with a single book, knowledge distillation, and tight feedback loops</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/4/</guid><description>I am writing this newsletter edition as NYC is being bombarded by hail. The sounds of little balls of ice ricocheting off of the roof has a sort of din to it that feels oddly comforting? In any case, your (bi) monthly dose of links from yours truly:
3 things I’ve found interesting The bookstore with a single book. This is a tiny bookstore in Tokyo that sells a single book at a time in a small room.</description></item><item><title>Sun sneezing, infrastructure moderation, and why bikes are better than tricycles</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/3/</guid><description>Hello there and welcome back to another issue of some mildly coherent ramblings. It&amp;rsquo;s been yet another couple busy weeks, but I&amp;rsquo;ve just wrapped up my second decade on this crazy planet! I have a lot of really exciting life updates that I want to share with all of you soon, but without further ado: the content you subscribed for.
3 things I’ve found interesting Context Collapse. Follow up to last issue&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;What&amp;rsquo;s not in the frame&amp;rsquo; question, I was finally able to put a name to a concept I&amp;rsquo;ve had floating around!</description></item><item><title>A request for coffee chats</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/1/</guid><description>This month of January went by with blazing speed. I can&amp;rsquo;t say if it&amp;rsquo;s because of school starting back up or just the massive amounts of s t u f f going on in the world right now.
On an unrelated note, I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on stepping outside my comfort zone and meeting new people so feel free to email back if you&amp;rsquo;d be interested in a coffee chat! I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to learn about all the cool things y&amp;rsquo;all are working on :)</description></item><item><title>Spider-man neurons, hearing fractals, and fulfilment</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/2/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t believe we&amp;rsquo;re approaching a time of year when I can wait until after dinner to turn on my desk light. In the almost two months since my last newsletter, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of reading, having 1:1s with some pretty rad people, learning Rust, and of course surviving school. Surviving, in this case, is a questionable word choice.
3 things I’ve found interesting Multimodal Neurons in Neural Networks.</description></item><item><title>Hello world!</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/newsletters/0/</guid><description>Hi there and thanks for signing up for my newsletter!
I’ll try to keep these in a rough 3-2-1 fashion in each issue, with 3 things I’ve found interesting from others, 2 things I’ve been wondering about, and 1 thing I’ve done.
3 things I’ve found interesting Found out about 100 Rabbits, a tag-team of two people sailing around the world making open-source software OpenAIs recent work with DALL-E and CLIP.</description></item></channel></rss>