<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 22:41:19 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Post-It Note City</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/post-it-note-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 22:41:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/post-it-note-city/</guid><description>Source Alphabet has the tools to design, build, fund, power, connect, monitor, and monetize a city, and that prospect scares people.
On Participatory Planning &amp;ldquo;Paper and ink, models and maps: these are the accessible tools of civic engagement — and corporate self-defense.&amp;rdquo;
Sidewalk lab&amp;rsquo;s choice to use the tools of civic design and participatory planning as a defense for their actions also strikes me as extremely cynical.</description></item><item><title>Consensus</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/consensus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 21:41:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/consensus/</guid><description>Consensus in human systems is actually usually pretty easy because of the social layer of society. This fault tolerance against 51% attacks is due to the fact that convincing the community that any engineered &amp;lsquo;truth&amp;rsquo; is the real on requires subverting every trusted member in the community, most notably media and news sources (also why systems of authoritarian power are so scary).</description></item><item><title>Proof of Work</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/proof-of-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 21:17:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/proof-of-work/</guid><description>Basis Cryptocurrencies use a distributed ledger (blockchain) to track all transactions in a publicly agreed upon manner.
All transactions are hashed. Hashing in general is a trivial function. To make it &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo;, the network sets a difficulty for how much work can be expected to &amp;ldquo;mine&amp;rdquo; a new block. Mining is essentially just working to find a valid hash for a batch of transactions. A &amp;lsquo;block&amp;rsquo; is a set of transactions.</description></item><item><title>Proof of Stake</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:34:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/proof-of-stake/</guid><description> Source TLDR; a set of validators take turns proposing and voting on the next block, and the weight of each validator’s vote depends on the size of its deposit (i.e. stake)
One of the alternatives to PoW Security comes from putting up economic value-at-loss rather than straight up burning energy
Disadvantages Greater chance of 51% attacks Incentive to hoard tokens and not use them</description></item><item><title>Quadratic Funding</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/quadratic-funding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:18:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/quadratic-funding/</guid><description>Sources: RadicalxChange and Vitalik Quadratic Funding (QF) is a more democratic and scalable form of matching funding for public goods, i.e. any projects valuable to large groups of people and accessible to the general public.
Matching funding is where governments or other institutions match individual contributions to a project.
In the QF model, the total funding is the square square root of each contribution summed and then squared. This empowers smaller individual contribution and make sure that a broad public benefits.</description></item><item><title>Decentralization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/decentralization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:12:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/decentralization/</guid><description>Source 3 Axes of Decentralizatiaon Architectural Decentralization: how many physical computers is a system made of? how many computers can fail before the network fails? Political Decentralization: how many individuals/organizations ultimately control the computers that the system is made up of? Logical Decentralization: are the data structures used to represent the system more monolithic or swarm-like? if you cut the system in half (both providers and users), will both halves continue to fully operate as independent units?</description></item><item><title>Computability</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/computability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 19:12:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/computability/</guid><description>The computational metaphor Source There is a creaking issue in universities where 70% of incoming students want to study computer science but only 5% of faculty is in computer science. What&amp;rsquo;s really going on is we want to study computer science as a proxy for the computational paradigm for everything around us
Is the universe computable? Implies the universe has finite precision.
Is there a computable $x$ for all $x$?</description></item><item><title>Ghost Work</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/ghost-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 12:17:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/ghost-work/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Funding</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/funding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:42:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/funding/</guid><description>Bounty Model Paying people set amounts for set tasks.
Bounty model is tough because
Immediate shared context is required and onboarding new members to do novel work is hard (upfront costs are large) Keeping people engaged after the tasks are difficult (no long term sense of investment) How can we keep individuals engaged with a project on longer term timescales?
Encouraging individuals to create projects with the technology/ideas (e.</description></item><item><title>Effective Altruism</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/effective-altruism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 23:52:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/effective-altruism/</guid><description>Very utilitarian, approach that the suffering of a few is okay as long as the greater good benefits? rel: The ones who walk from Omelas What is EA? Earning to give. How do we reduce the stigma around wealth?
Work can have huge impacts on the type of change we can make in the world. We spend ~80k hours, makes sense to spend atleast 1% of it thinking about what to dedicate the other 99% to.</description></item><item><title>Accountability</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/accountability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 23:27:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/accountability/</guid><description>reparations and reconciliation can only occur after both parties have acknowledged it how does this work if one party &amp;lsquo; ghosts &amp;rsquo; or otherwise leaves the conversation? emotional labour goes up in a democratic setting when more people are involved (rel: group limits ) is there a point where it is almost always better to have an authoritarian/impersonal third party? (e.g. the state and the law) how do we keep people accountable in digital spaces and virtual worlds ?</description></item><item><title>Longevity</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/longevity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:18:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/longevity/</guid><description>How much of human existence is just us trying to create impact beyond our incredibly short lifespans?
Permanent land preserves, the Global Seed Vault, the internet itself as the foundational communications technology of a global age. These are not only public goods , they are the cultural practices that maintain such goods over generations.
Money is power, and many are already looking for ambitious and impactful ways to spend their billion-dollar treasuries.</description></item><item><title>Progress</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/progress/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 15:26:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/progress/</guid><description>From 21 Lesson for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari: &amp;ldquo;Did we domesticate wheat or did wheat domesticate us?&amp;rdquo; So much of technological progress is conflated as a good thing. Is it necessarily so?
Progress, loosely defined by Tyler Cowen and Patrick Collison , is &amp;ldquo;the combination of economic, technological, scientific, cultural, and organizational advancement that has transformed our lives and raised standards of living over the past couple of centuries&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>A new DARPA</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/a-new-darpa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:10:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/a-new-darpa/</guid><description>Money is power. It dictates what type of research and work gets funded, and who gets to do it.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of the incentive structures in place wherever you work (e.g. academia, industry): 80k hours of work in your life, it matters a lot where that goes (voting with labour).
As of now, there are no good spaces to work on long-term (think 10+ years in the future) research to enable the visions of the future.</description></item><item><title>Memory Palace</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/memory-palace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 21:07:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/memory-palace/</guid><description>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_of_loci
Can we create associations between digital/physical space and concept space? Create a digital library of our concepts and ideas?
Better ways to browse/discover ideas and concepts More from Bret Victor and DynamicLand: http://worrydream.com/cdg/ResearchAgenda-v0.19-poster.pdf
Creating a browsable store of knowledge that provides something useful at all distance scales (e.g. viewing the entire library, just a subcategory, a single file, etc.)
Create a spatially-anchored overview of the different &amp;lsquo;branches&amp;rsquo; of knowledge</description></item><item><title>Tragedy of the Commons</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/tragedy-of-the-commons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 18:59:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/tragedy-of-the-commons/</guid><description>The more accessible a good is, the less people want to pay for it. &amp;ndash; Scott Moore A government only has interest in funding its own roads, companies like Facebook only have interest in funding their own infrastructure. Very prevalent in open-source , some of the most used software in the world often goes unpaid and unfunded.
Commons in the modern economic context is any open-access and unregulated resource (e.</description></item><item><title>Public Goods</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/public-goods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 18:49:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/public-goods/</guid><description>GitCoin RFP Proposal Definitions Public goods are
non-excludable: it’s extremely difficult to stop someone from using the good, like roads and bridges non-rivalrous: it’s abundant, and one person’s use of the good doesn’t substantially reduce the amount left for someone else (e.g. there’s more than enough air to go around) It costs the same to produce for one person as it is for everyone else, and one cannot prevent people from accessing this.</description></item><item><title>DAO</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/dao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 18:46:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/dao/</guid><description>https://linda.mirror.xyz/Vh8K4leCGEO06_qSGx-vS5lvgUqhqkCz9ut81WwCP2o
DAOs give us structured ways to collect , invest , and build together.
Inherently transparent, every aspect of the org is public.
The most infamous DAO, The DAO , was a decentralized VC fund. Eventually raised $150M but had $60M hacked, leaving a negative impression/skepticism around DAOs for a while.
Stable employment is possible through DAOs, Empty Set Dollar DAO is paying a $180k salary to their community manager</description></item><item><title>Social Contracts</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-contracts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 18:41:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-contracts/</guid><description>Social contracts are implicit agreements among members of social groups to cooperate for social benefits. They help us form shared cultures and values
Rousseau -&amp;gt; everyone forfeits some rights so that they might also impose selected duties
e.g. most democracies today, citizens agree to pay taxes in their shared currencies to fund and maintain basic infrastructure like roads, bridges, and electrical grids</description></item><item><title>Web3</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/web3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:13:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/web3/</guid><description>While crypto protocols operate as open networks, do they truly enact a public if solely comprised of private capital?
Crypto systems are interesting, they are &amp;ldquo;decentralized, jurisdictionless entities that exist entirely in cyberspace, maintained by a combination of cryptography, economics and social consensus &amp;rdquo;
The cyberpunkspirit: the basic property of which adverserial conflict continues to heavily favour the defender. It should be much more expensive to destroy or disrupt than they are to use and maintain &amp;ndash; Vitalkik Buterin Index Decentralization Public Goods DAOs Quadratic Funding Proof of stake Proof of work Consensus Web History https://ethereum.</description></item><item><title>Silicon Valley: An unrepeatable miracle?</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/unrepeatable-miracle-of-silicon-valley/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:11:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/unrepeatable-miracle-of-silicon-valley/</guid><description>https://www.aei.org/economics/silicon-valley-an-unrepeatable-miracle-a-long-read-qa-with-margaret-omara/
Podcast Interview with Margaret O’Mara, the author of The Code: Silicon Valley and the Remaking of America
Touches on a lot of similar topics to From Counterculture to Cyberculture What caused the big influx of extraordinary opportunity in Northern California, despite mostly being another sleepy fruit-growing region? Mostly the result of the Cold War and the military-industrial complex and the power of Stanford &amp;ndash; these two were not completely separate.</description></item><item><title>Workflows</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/workflows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 17:03:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/workflows/</guid><description>https://uxdesign.cc/introducing-mercury-os-f4de45a04289
Creating modular tools for users to build their own workflows &amp;ldquo;Each person’s mind works a little differently, and each person remembers and processes information a little differently. I think we all work at our best when we work with tools that fit how our minds work.&amp;rdquo;
When other people build tools for us to use, they either design tools after their own workflows and mental models, or worse, they design it for a mass market of millions of people who all sort-of-but-not-really work and think in similar ways.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Touch</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/beyond-touch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:47:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/beyond-touch/</guid><description>Humanity is using the dynamic medium merely to emulate and extend static representations from the era of paper.
New representations of thought — written language, numerals, mathematical notation, data graphics — have been responsible for some of the most significant leaps in the progress of civilization, by expanding humanity’s collectively-thinkable territory. Why then, have we been trapped using the desktop/paper metaphor for the last few centuries?
And what about screens as a whole?</description></item><item><title>Originality</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/originality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:29:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/originality/</guid><description>Is anything ever new? Is everything derivative
Lavoisier once said: &amp;ldquo;Rien ne se perd, rien ne se crée, tout se transforme&amp;rdquo; —meaning &amp;ldquo;Nothing is lost, nothing is created, everything is transformed.&amp;rdquo; (when applied to fundamental physics)
Ideas are mostly recombination, does this imply that everything comes from one &amp;lsquo;original&amp;rsquo; idea?</description></item><item><title>Group Limits</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/group-limits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:03:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/group-limits/</guid><description>The Dunbar number https://www.newyorker.com/science/maria-konnikova/social-media-affect-math-dunbar-number-friendships
There&amp;rsquo;s only so big a social group can get before it decays into smaller ones.
Social Brain Hypothesis -&amp;gt; primates have large brains because they live in socially complex societies: the larger the group, the larger the brain
Applied to humans, Dunbar computed a theoretical maximum of 150 for human social groups.
A range (by a factor of 3)
Casual Friends -&amp;gt; 150 &amp;lsquo;Dinner&amp;rsquo; Friends -&amp;gt; 50 Close Friends -&amp;gt; 15 Intimate Friends -&amp;gt; 5 Can we scale trust beyond the Dunbar number?</description></item><item><title>Contact Language</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/contact-language/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 21:18:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/contact-language/</guid><description>Digital Contact Languages The rise of the Kindle points out that even the concept of a link—a “uniform resource locator,” or URL—is under great stress. Since Kindle books don’t live on the World Wide Web, there’s no URL pointing to a particular page or passage of them. The same goes for content within any number of mobile apps, leaving people to trade screenshots—or, as The Atlantic’s Kaitlyn Tiffany put it , “the gremlins of the internet”—as a way of conveying content.</description></item><item><title>Digital Commons</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-commons/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 17:51:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-commons/</guid><description>https://mmm.page/helena.soft_tech
&amp;ldquo;what if you had to commute to websites&amp;rdquo; https://twitter.com/spencerc99/status/1401320086183366657
How might we analogize urban planning to social media and digital spaces? -&amp;gt; https://medium.com/@jasminewsun/jane-jacobs-social-media-83b4265a1d12
Creating Digital Spaces Can we create digital common spaces like parks and things without everyone online needing to be exceedingly intentioned?
Commons should be safe, low pressure contexts for random interaction. They are public spaces where a lot of people coincidentally share the same space for a short period in time.</description></item><item><title>Climate Tech</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/climate-tech/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 17:28:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/climate-tech/</guid><description>Not just about investing in carbon removal or carbon offsets also about investing in the infrastructure to make it possible
The Land Ethic simply enlarges the boundaries of the community to include soils, waters, plants, and animals, or collectively: the land. It changes the role of Homo sapiens from conqueror of the landcommunity to plain member and citizen of it.
Carbon Credits Source Can we create &amp;lsquo;credits&amp;rsquo; that companies can buy to offset their emissions by &amp;lsquo;proving&amp;rsquo; that a forest is sequestering a certain amount of carbon?</description></item><item><title>Communities</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</guid><description>Types of Communities Interest-based → same interests/passions Location-based → same geographical location, place of work, etc. Vibe-based → group energy Circumstance-based → external influence, put into the same group Can we ever have fully digital commons ?
How large can communities get before they decay? Relevant: group limits Ingroup/outgroup biases get social status points we will choose to identify with whatever in-group will immediately benefit us the most why soririties + frats are successful → sunk cost falacy amount of boundaries required → well organized events vs serendipitous interactions do serendipitous interactions only come from ephemereal content ?</description></item><item><title>Multiple Realization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/multiple-realization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 18:17:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/multiple-realization/</guid><description>Are there multiple ways of realizing intelligence?
the bitter lesson → http://www.incompleteideas.net/IncIdeas/BitterLesson.html
a bitter lesson reframing data? speech data → audio features / mfcc inadvertently taking away the ability to make new insights based of restrictions how do we explore more of the solution space feedforward → linear relationships sigmoid → non-linear what other solution spaces are we missing do we necessarily need human intelligence for machine intelligence?</description></item><item><title>Software and Politics</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/software-and-politics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:41:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/software-and-politics/</guid><description>Artificacts have Politics https://www.jstor.org/stable/20024652
https://sbuss.substack.com/p/politics-for-software-engineers-part-2 &amp;ldquo;Blockchain voting addresses how to vote in a trust-less society, but a trust-less society cannot have a functioning democracy.&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; error-handling Potential use of Merkle Trees? (but also, city-is-not-a-tree )
Simplicity is more important that provably correct &amp;ldquo;I think where most software engineers fail at politics, it&amp;rsquo;s in understanding that key point. We tend to over engineer our systems and never need to explain the inner workings to anyone who is non-technical.</description></item><item><title>Life Definition</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/life-definition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 21:38:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/life-definition/</guid><description>Matthews Ozma of oz Tik-Tok → &amp;ldquo;Thinks, Speaks, Acts, and Does Everything but Live&amp;rdquo; Tin Man vs Tik-Tok Tin Man used to be living (born a real man) but lost his body over time due to a series of wood chopping &amp;lsquo;accidents&amp;rsquo; a modern tale of the ship of Theseus does the original entity persist through the gradual replacement of each of its parts, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, where does it stop being the same entity?</description></item><item><title>Telerobotics</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/telerobotics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 21:37:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/telerobotics/</guid><description>Clark &amp;ldquo;distance is what there is no action at&amp;rdquo; draw the lines of proximity and distance according to the criterion of effective action Dennett&amp;rsquo;s 1981 &amp;ldquo;where am I&amp;rdquo; story secret experiment, Dennett&amp;rsquo;s brain is remove, kept alive in a tank of nutrients, and equipped with a multitude of radio links by means of which it executes all of its normal bodily control functions Dennet&amp;rsquo;s body is then equipped with receivers and transmitters so that it can use its built-in sensors (eyes, ears, etc.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Worlds</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/virtual-worlds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 16:23:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/virtual-worlds/</guid><description>Personal Thoughts Bridging the real and the virtual moving away from personal computing started off with timeshare personal computing now streaming EVERYTHING to the cloud devices will just be viewing places https://www.mightyapp.com/ No matter how hard we try, our virtual selves will inevitably be tethered to our physical selves. Interface with these virtual worlds through looking at our screens, typing on our keyboards, etc. even with a pseudonymous-web that is not supposedly tied to anything in the physical realm.</description></item><item><title>Mind-Body Problem</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/mind-body-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:43:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/mind-body-problem/</guid><description>Crane understanding the brain may be the best path to understanding minds The mind-body problem how the mind and body are connected to one another are we just entirely made up of matter or is there something more? two points of doubt we know a bit about minds without knowing anything about brains are minds different from brains not true, they still might be the same thing materialism (physicalism) → minds and brains are identical (identity theory) nothing magical about minds, just the brains activity dualism → minds are distinct from the brain idealism → everything is mental/in the mind considering other minds for own mind → introspection works, more or less for other minds → must rely on behaviour of others (what they say and do) two possible ways of understanding how this way of knowing other minds works behaviourism → behaviour is all there is to mentality seems inconsistent w introspection we have thoughts that are never reflected in our behaviour can have multiple thoughts that correspond with a behaviour → umbrella example a man looks out of a window, goes to a closet and takes an umbrella before leaving his house what is he thinking?</description></item><item><title>Language of Thought</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/language-of-thought/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/language-of-thought/</guid><description>Can we use language as the method of querying memory?
Crane Language of thought hypothesis → LOTH proposes thinking occurs in a mental language, this is called mentalese computations in a classical way classical computational architecture distinguishes between data-structures and rules/programs which operate on said structures sequential processing rather than parallel &amp;lsquo;rules and representations picture&amp;rsquo; sometimes called GOFAI neural networks or connectionist computational models challenges any argument for mentalese architecture large number of units which are connected to others (connectionism) and the connections have different strengths (weights) units are arranged in layers computation happens in parallel like in a classical machine, representations are assigned to connectionist networks by the people who build them two types of connectionist representation localist → each unit is assigned a feature as a whole that represents distributed → state of the network as a whole represents something often claimed to be one of the distinctive features of connectionism connectionist networks is sometimes called parallel distributed processing (PDP) can be trained to learn resemble the structure of the brain much more closely than any classical computer really good at pattern recognition Putnam Turing Test dialogic test of competence exploring the notion of reference are the things the machine refers to the same things we refer to?</description></item><item><title>Representation</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/representation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:33:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/representation/</guid><description>Crane Symbolic Representation mans just kinda doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree w/ the pioneer 10 space probe plate lmao symbols will not mean anything to any alien life we find it easy to understand because we have the context and we live on this planet words do not have meaning in and of themselves (no intrinsic meaning) what sort of things can be representations words/pictures/numbers/diagrams state of mind, can represent almost anything at all what sort of things can be objects of representations almost anything (physical objects, sentences, numbers, moods, feelings, emotions, non-existent things) pictures represent by resemblance → derivative intention ‘resemblance theory of pictorial representation’, or the &amp;lsquo;resemblance theory&amp;rsquo; WC ant argument, resemblance is not enough for reference X represents Y → suggests that representation is a relation between two things is there a basic type of representation underlying everything else?</description></item><item><title>Mind Design</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/mind-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:27:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/mind-design/</guid><description>Haugeland 1 → what is mind design? understand the mind in terms of its design (how its built/works) → a form of cognitive psychology ai would fall under mind design, more about building things and making it work rather than analyzing what already exists psychology by reverse engineering is a materialist → the mind is nothing but matter in motion &amp;hellip; realize that things can be viewed from different perspectives (or described in different terms) –and, when we look differently, what we are able to see is also different” (p.</description></item><item><title>Symbolic Systems</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/symbolic-systems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:05:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/symbolic-systems/</guid><description>Dreyfus Convergence of CS and Philosophy newell and simon claimed that both digital computers and the human mind could be understood as physical symbol systems using strings of bits or streams of neuron pulses as symbols representing the external world intelligence (as claimed by newell and simon) required making the appropriate inference from these internal representations &amp;ldquo;a physical symbol system has the necessary and sufficient means for general intelligent action&amp;rdquo; turning rationalist philosophy into a research program hobbes → reasoning was calculating descartes → mental representations leibniz → &amp;ldquo;universal characteristic&amp;rdquo; — a set of primitives in which all knowledge could be expresse kant → concepts are rules russell → logical atoms as the building blocks of reality Symbolic AI as a degenerating research program problem of representing significance and relevance → how do you transfer the learnings to the real world heidegger values are just meaningless facts (hammer is for hammering), leaves out information defining the relation of hammers to nails and the rest of the environment (readiness-to-hand) commonsense knowledge problem → how do we represent &amp;lsquo;common sense&amp;rsquo; in a way that is accessible to AI systems that use natural language problem isnt curating those facts, it&amp;rsquo;s knowing which facts are relevant in any given situations (the frame-problem ) should be able to ignore something without having to figure out that it should ignore it if the computer is running a representation of the current state of the world and something in the world chances, how does the program determine which of its represented facts can be assumed to have stayed the same, and which would have to be updated?</description></item><item><title>Embedded AI</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/embedded-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:01:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/embedded-ai/</guid><description>Dreyfus Why Heideggerian AI failed and how fixing it would require making it more Heideggerian the frame approach → descriptions of typical situations like going to a birthday party however, this quickly grows out of hand once again as any AI program using frames to organize millions of meaningless facts so as to retrieve the relevant frames is going to be caught in a cycle of finding frames for recognizing relevant frames for recognizing relvant facts an emergent heideggerian cognitive science → embodied-embedded thinking is under active investigation and development john haugeland → cognition is embedded and embodied Three approaches to supposedly Heideggerian AI Rodney Brook&amp;rsquo;s behaviourist approach it turns out to be very difficult to reproduce in an internal representation for a computer the necessary richness of environment that would give rise to interesting behaviour by a highly adaptive robot this is avoided by human beings because their model of the world is the world itself &amp;ldquo;the best model of the world is the world itself&amp;rdquo; build a mobile robot that uses the world itself as its own representation (referring to its sensors rather than to an internal world model) problems does not learn operates in a fixed world, responding only to a small set of possibly relevant features that their receptors can pick up Phil Agre&amp;rsquo;s pragmatist model use of deictic representations instead of representing a particular object in the world represent a role that an object might play in a certain time-extended pattern of interaction between an agent and its environment objectified both functions and situational relevance for the agent e.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 14:03:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/machine-learning/</guid><description>Haugeland GOFAI (good old-fashioned AI) this view believes that the mind is a computer with certain special characteristics — namely the fact that its internal states and processes can be regarded as thinking or reasoning finding meaning in a body of symbols, like finding rationality in a body of behaviour, is finding a certain kind of consistent, reliable pattern problem solvers often use canny, methodical exploration neither algorithmic nor random a familiar sort of articulate reasoning or thinking a problem out &amp;ldquo;if only i could get that, then I could nail this down; but in order to get that, I would need such and such&amp;rdquo; GOFAI is very narrow-minded and vulnerable to unexpected variations and oddities in the problems and information they were given grounded in the possibility of translation — semantic interpretation NFAI (new-fangled AI) falls under connectionism and connectionist networks can retain memory short term → spiking neural networks, information within the system changes slowly long term → within connections themselves (weights and biases) adept at finding various sort of similarities among patterns, at recognizing repeated (or almost repeated) patterns and filling in missing parts of incomplete patterns NFAI learns from examples (but not in the same way humans do) connectionist mind design → relies on computers the same way a weather service does, to simulate digitally systems that are not in themselves digital inspired by the structure of the brain, but more deeply, by the importance and ubiquity of non-formal pattern reasoning very grab-bag term → anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t GOFAI argument that a lot of human intelligence is not embodied in anyone, its a part of the world e.</description></item><item><title>Semantics: What is Meaning?</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/semantics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:49:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/semantics/</guid><description>Putnam meanings are public property → the same meaning be grasped by more than one person and by persons at different times Putnam&amp;rsquo;s argument my twin is thinking of XYZ and I am thinking of H2O XYZ ≠ H2O content determines object (frege: the sense of a term determines its referent) if t1 and t2 have different objects, then they must also have different content twin and I have thoughts with different content thoughts are individuated by their content twin and I h ave different thoughts even though we are molecule-for-molecule duplicates Implications if this argument is correct, then the content of our thoughts partly depends on what is in the world we live in (we can&amp;rsquo;t be BIVs) content determines object what about indexical thoughts?</description></item><item><title>Frame Problem</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/frame-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:36:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/frame-problem/</guid><description>Dennet Frame problem of AI coined by McCarthy and Hayes → particular narrowly conceived problem about representation call the broader problem &amp;ldquo;the whole pudding&amp;rdquo; will refer to &amp;ldquo;the whole pudding&amp;rdquo; as the frame problem intelligence is (at least partly) a matter of using well what you know an intelligent being learns from experience, and then uses what is has learned to guide expectations in the futrue hume believed that we &amp;lsquo;think before we leap&amp;rsquo; because of associationism → certain transition paths between ideas grew more likely-to-be-followed as they became well worn dennet thinks this is flawed, hume operates at a purely semantic level (phenomenological level), one assumes that items behave as items with those meanings ought to behave hetero-phenomenologist → one reasons about what the agent must know or figure out either unconsciously or consciously in order to perform various tasks AI → is formulated tabula rasa (from scratch, no knowledge about the the world) everything either needs to be impressed by programmer at the outset subsequent learning by the system Installation problem problem of installing in one way or another all the information needed by an agent to plan in a changing world</description></item><item><title>Can Machines Think?</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/intelligence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:29:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/intelligence/</guid><description>Intelligence as a measure of information conversation ratio. How do we test intelligence of machines vs humans?
Intelligence can only be contextually based on information available. There are no intrinsically difficult questions, only wrt inputs
Dretske Can intelligence be artificial? two ways of thinking about it like money → everyone has, some have more than others philosophers view like wealth → something possessed by only those who have more than the average amount of money computer scientists view thought alone is not enough, the thoughts need to do something, and sometimes explain the doing actions that are not governed by/explained by thought are not intelligent in order to be intelligent, the behaviour must be under the control of the content of the thought and not the vehicle of the content plant analogy even if you know what physical events inside the plant are causing the change in colour, don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily know why the plant is changing colour could be a result to encouraging different polinators or discouraging beetles from eating it what about laboratory grown?</description></item><item><title>Extended Mind</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/extended-mind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:18:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/extended-mind/</guid><description>Sterelny Minds: extended or scaffolded?
Extended view of the mind not an internal control system, enclosed in the human body, receiving data from human sensory system and directing human action instead, as systems that extend far beyond the body of the human organism, systems that include extra-somatic resources: environmental fuels for adaptive action suggest that human cognitive systems include those resources that are importantly, robustly, reliably, or persistently supportive of decisions making Theory of Niche Construction many animals intervene in their environment, shaping it in ways that improve the adaptive fit between the agent and its world such animals in part adapt to their niche, in part construct their own the niche construction perspective focuses our attention on the common features of this whole range of cases whereas the extended mind model does not human capacities, cognitive and non-cognitive alike, turn out to depend on the fact that humans engineer their environment to support their activities extended digestion example some animals do the hard digestion stuff on-board, powerful jaws, large mouths, lots of time chewing we cook lmao also, we selectively breed livestock which improves the food value of domestic stock Extended Phenotypes Concept things animals build are part of their phenotype (physical exhibited traits that are determined genetically) developmentally stable, as heritable and predictable in their ecological effects as other traits e.</description></item><item><title>On Idolization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/on-idolization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 23:36:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/on-idolization/</guid><description>https://blog.matthewwang.me/life/concise21/2021/03/01/on-idolization.html
&amp;ldquo;I struggled with this significantly in high school. I had the pleasure of working with some absolutely wonderful people. We debated together and against each other; ran conferences and events; did community service. I’d constantly rave about how insane, out of the world, and unbelievable they were. It was constant and nagging. It seeped into my personality.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You implicitly invalidate any struggles they have, and eschew their private life. Your praise becomes so diluted that it’s meaningless, just another reflex or polite gesture.</description></item><item><title>To Live in their Utopia</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/to-live-in-their-utopia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:13:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/to-live-in-their-utopia/</guid><description>https://ali-alkhatib.com/papers/chi/utopia/utopia.pdf https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ClGIosevT0Y
Design and Developement of Systems Creation vs Maintenance view of developing AI:
Creation: &amp;ldquo;focus on finding new places and ways to use technologies and new insights that AI might yield when ML is applied to massive datasets to find relationships in the data&amp;rdquo; Maintenance: &amp;ldquo;surfaces problems with existing systems and attempts to mitigate those harms (for instance, by making them more fair, accountable, and transparent)&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;When designers of these algorithmic systems train computational models that ignore transgender identity, these systems demand that trans people somehow shed an identity they can&amp;rsquo;t; identities that cisgender people hardly ever bother to regard.</description></item><item><title>Fault Tolerance</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</guid><description>Fault Tolerance How do we defend against attacks in distributed systems with no central authority?
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault https://lamport.azurewebsites.net/pubs/byz.pdf
Zooko&amp;rsquo;s Triangle Postulates that names of participants can have at most 2 of these 3 properties
Human-meaningful: Meaningful and memorable (low-entropy) names are provided to the users. Secure: The amount of damage a malicious entity can inflict on the system should be as low as possible. Decentralized: Names correctly resolve to their respective entities without the use of a central authority or service.</description></item><item><title>Creation vs Maintenance</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/creation-vs-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:07:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/creation-vs-maintenance/</guid><description>So much of today&amp;rsquo;s society revolves around creating new things rather than maintaining existing things. Yet, the two go hand in hand - innovation without the ability to scale and maintain is frivolous, and maintenance without innovation is stagnation.
There is importance in indigenous knowledge and tradition.
Web3: shouldering the cost of maintenance among the users rather than centralizing it with the creators
Do Eastern vs Western cultures have diff takes on this?</description></item><item><title>The Ones Who Walk from Omelas</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/the-ones-who-walk-from-omelas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 09:14:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/the-ones-who-walk-from-omelas/</guid><description>http://sites.asiasociety.org/asia21summit/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/3.-Le-Guin-Ursula-The-Ones-Who-Walk-Away-From-Omelas.pdf
There is no happiness without suffering. The story presents a classic utilitarian problem: is it morally justifiable to inflict suffering on one person in the service of others’ happiness?
Thinking about it in terms of technology as a multiplicative tool. Is it then morally just to develop technology to benefit others knowing that it will exacerbate the suffering of marginalized groups? Follow up: is there any way we can use tech as a running shoe instead of a crutch?</description></item><item><title>Research Debt</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/research-debt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:34:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/research-debt/</guid><description>https://distill.pub/2017/research-debt/
Partly works because we can utilize collaborative thinking Thinking about understanding knowledge as climbing a mountain. Everytime novel work happens, the mountain gets a little bit taller.
Mathematics is a striking example of this. For centuries, countless minds have climbed the mountain range of mathematics and laid new boulders at the top. Over time, different peaks formed, built on top of particularly beautiful results. Now the peaks of mathematics are so numerous and steep that no person can climb them all.</description></item><item><title>Academia</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:13:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</guid><description>Cool People/Things http://jeffclune.com/ https://www.davidlindlbauer.com/ https://www.hcii.cmu.edu/summer-research-program https://chrisharrison.net/index.php/Research/Welcome
Tunnel Vision https://www.briantimar.com/notes/mimetic/mimetic/ Graduate programs select for intensely competitive individuals with highly specific skills, often with negligible market value outside of universities. A strong desire for publications on esoteric topics is inherited from senior postdocs and professors, making tunnel vision especially acute.
Incentive Structure Academia feels more pure, more like play? More of a &amp;lsquo;constructionist&amp;rsquo; approach, freedom to ask your own questions rel: mindstorms Thinking about how similar the incentive structures are in hackathons Can we create the energy of DARPA outside of government funding ?</description></item><item><title>Exploit Explore Problem</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/exploit-explore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:32:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/exploit-explore/</guid><description>https://towardsdatascience.com/intro-to-reinforcement-learning-the-explore-exploit-dilemma-463ceb004989
exploit-explore tradeoff in ML hill climbing/optimization problem always jump to next step up → greedy search optimizing to find one&amp;rsquo;s true values https://www.samsonzhang.com/2021/01/26/the-joy-of-wasting-time-the-exploration-exploitation-tradeoff-of-life.html &amp;ldquo;The ideal is to find an equilibrium point between external pulls and internal pushes, between exploitation (of your current opportunities via external pulls) and exploration (of your actual passions via internal pushes)&amp;hellip; the process of finding equilibrium often takes the form of a damped oscillation over time&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Feedback Loops</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:32:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</guid><description>Newsletter bit https://brianlui.dog/2020/05/10/beware-of-tight-feedback-loops/
noise in social media used to be a town square → hear what you hear radio bar model → everyone has a frequency people chose their frequency (substack model) competing on substack vs rolling your own centaur systems human feedback loops extended cognition with centaur systems Imitation https://www.briantimar.com/notes/mimetic/mimetic/ The second was a positive feedback loop that encouraged me to spend ever-increasing amounts of time on my work.</description></item><item><title>Pseudonymous Web</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/pseudonymous-web/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:57:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/pseudonymous-web/</guid><description>https://qualiaspace.substack.com/p/the-future-of-social-media-is-pseudonymous
An identity-based social graph is fundamentally limited. Your Facebook identity and social graph are mere digital shadows of their physical counterparts, and little more.
By attaching our real-world identities to everything we do, these platforms feel suffocating and unsafe. Is there any way we can construct fully virtual worlds not tethered to reality? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we can.
&amp;ldquo;In real life and on Facebook, you’re always signaling information about yourself which may not have anything to do with the context you’re in.</description></item><item><title>Cities and Programming</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/cities-and-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/cities-and-programming/</guid><description>http://tomasp.net/blog/2020/cities-and-programming/
Mostly about maintenance of cities and parallels with maintaining software.
urban-planning Brand argues that many great buildings achieved their greatness by gradual stepwise evolution over time. New buildings need to be designed with the expectation that they will evolve, because they usually outlive their initial use. Even if a building does not change its use (e.g. it remains the same university department), the needs of its users will change and the building will need to adapt.</description></item><item><title>Project Idea List</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/project-list/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:33:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/project-list/</guid><description>Continuations Desktop Portal Creating a desktop version of portal for easier UX
Ideas Tools for Thought block based editors are neat cause i can move stuff around really easily if u drag outside the page it makes a new note, super easy to break down big complex topics into more granular/atomic notes spatially consistent? memory palace vibes -&amp;gt; https://twitter.com/jordanmoore/status/1418942880941477891 card based backlinks/outgoing links on the left, you can see all the notes that link to the current page on the right, you can see all outoing links hovering on each card will reveal another layer which those ones are connected to graph view i wanted to have the option for 3d graphs too timeline view each note will come with a date so you can chronologically order notes and view them that way (kind of like a git history) if ur brain works better that way good global search being able to index content fast and effectively Long Term Archival Storage Service DreamCoder boolsat Creating a LISP-like higher-order language to exploit reusable sub-proofs in specific domains (e.</description></item><item><title>Attention Economy</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:27:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</guid><description>Attention as a commodity, it is increasingly competitive to compete for everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention
shortening of attention spans? not sure if this is an actual thing &amp;lsquo;digital detox&amp;rsquo; people not just as the products, but as the producers of the product (data) Attention is the main currency of production &amp;ndash; what limits you from doing everything at once. Attention, then, is a common pool resource. It is non-excludable (anyone can bid for their attention) and rivalrous (limited attention).</description></item><item><title>Emergent Behaviour</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/emergent-behaviour/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:21:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/emergent-behaviour/</guid><description>How complex behaviour can arise out of seemingly simple rules
Ant simulations Mold simulations Community dynamics Interesting to think about in context of single agents in multi-agent systems How does consciousness arise?
Even in systems of representation ,</description></item><item><title>A City is not a Tree</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/city-is-not-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 20:39:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/city-is-not-a-tree/</guid><description>https://www.patternlanguage.com/archive/cityisnotatree.html
Why trees instead of graphs Both the tree and the semilattice are ways of thinking about how a large collection of many small systems goes to make up a large and complex system. More generally, they are both names for structures of sets.
For the human mind, the tree is the easiest vehicle for complex thoughts. But the city is not, cannot and must not be a tree. The city is a receptacle for life.</description></item><item><title>Building in Public</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;He who works with the door open gets all kinds of interruptions, but he also occasionally gets clues as to what the world is and what might be important.&amp;rdquo; — richard hamming
https://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/YouAndYourResearch.html invite distractions but get a better sense of the world</description></item><item><title>Ephemereal Content</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</guid><description>moving towards live ephemerality pandemic accelerated blending of async and sycn convos One of the things that keeps face-to-face friendships strong is the nature of shared experience : you laugh together; you dance together; you gape at the hot-dog eaters on Coney Island together.
video movies vlogs vine/tiktoks text email sms snapchat messages https://honk.me/ Opposite of digital permanence It is really tempting to cover for mistakes by pretending they never happened.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</guid><description>What is infrastructure even? which came first, the infrastructure or the applications that depend on it? things that use infrastructure or technology in the beginning not much of a distinction first tech → language how did language arise? evolve with each other? language as infrastructure for thought at a certain complexity level, combinatorial explosion of complexity does it grows as emergent behaviour ? is any infrastructure ever new?</description></item><item><title>Social Graphs</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</guid><description>social graph → who&amp;rsquo;s connected to who interest graph → online representations of interests constructing interest graphs from social graphs traditional social media apps like facebook/ig constructing social graphs from interest graphs more &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; apps like tiktok social graph as infrastructure? should we make one centralized social structure and platforms can then build platforms off of that social graph? china does this well focus on being end product rather than infrastructure layer that others build on top of &amp;ldquo;a platform is when the economic value of everybody that uses it exceeds the value of the company that creates it.</description></item><item><title>Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</guid><description>notes from A people-centric smart city for racial justice cities are the backbone and hope of social change either great benefit but also digital cages of surveillance and control what is the role of cities in the post-pandemic phase? laboratories for democratic and sustainable innovations smart, equitable, democratic cities tech has market AND social power 9T market cap, more than the entirety of european stock market IMPORTANT QUESTIONS smart for whom?</description></item><item><title>Mindstorms</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/mindstorms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/mindstorms/</guid><description>Quotes Constructionism &amp;ldquo;As children construct things in the world, they construct new ideas and theories in their minds, which motivates them to construct new things in the world, and on and on.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I never met anyone who was, at once, so playful and so serious about ideas.&amp;rdquo;
Piaget has demonstrated that children learn fundamental mathematical ideas by first building their own, very much different (for example, preconservationist) mathematics. And children learn language by first learning their own (&amp;ldquo;baby-talk&amp;rdquo;) dialects.</description></item><item><title>From Counterculture to Cyberculture</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/fctc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/fctc/</guid><description>Quotes Digital Communalism &amp;ldquo;Ubiquitous networked computing had arrived, and in its shiny array of interlinked devices, pundits, scholars, and investors alike saw the image of an ideal society: decentralized, egalitarian, harmonious, and free&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;In The Gutenberg Galaxy McLuhan described the new age in tribal terms: electronic media had linked all of humanity into a single &amp;lsquo;global vilage&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Nor does the fact that individuals can come together by means of ocmputer networks necessarily require that their gatherings become &amp;lsquo;virtual communities&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Design Justice</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/design-justice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:58:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/design-justice/</guid><description>Summary Design Justice focuses not just on design in the visual and aesthetic sense, but also on the design of systems.
To quote from the book, &amp;ldquo;Design justice rethinks design processes, centers people who are normally marginalized by design, and uses collaborative, creative practices to address the deepest challenges our communities face.&amp;rdquo; The norms, values, and assumptions that are encoded and reproduced in the design of systems can be changed by rethinking our design processes.</description></item><item><title>Introductions</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/introductions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 19:47:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/introductions/</guid><description>why i can never do good introductions
apply labels to things people have expectations self-imposed as well first of many experiences → why do we feel the need to get it right at the start? Intersectional Identities &amp;ldquo;A man may be regarded as the point of intersection of an indefinite number of circles representing social groups&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; - Cooley, Human Nature and the Social Order (1922)</description></item><item><title>Catch 22</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:28:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</guid><description>If a pilot is deemed insane, they don&amp;rsquo;t have to fly. To be deemed insane, a pilot must request to be evaluated. If a pilot requests to be evaluated, this demonstrates that he must be sane. Therefore, no pilot can ever be deemed insane, and no pilot can get out of flying. paradoxical sitauation -&amp;gt; catch-22
no way to win double bind -&amp;gt; a psychological predicament in which a person receives from a single source conflicting messages that allow no appropriate response to be made</description></item><item><title>Search or be found</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 21:46:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</guid><description>The search box versus the feed intentional browsing vs being served by an algorithm
Is it possible to move away from the ‘feed’-based model of browsing the social internet?
The “feed”–an archaic form of content consumption that is effectively just a direct visual manifestation of the data structure that powers it – is a medium that is effectively designed to be consumed alone. –Humphrey Obuobi
&amp;ldquo;I realized that the experience of research is exactly opposite to the way I usually often encounter information online.</description></item><item><title>Digital Permanence</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</guid><description>Once you share something, you can&amp;rsquo;t unshare it, internet feels intractable
https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/06/the-internet-is-a-collective-hallucination/619320/: &amp;ldquo;Of course, there’s a keenly related problem of permanency for much of what’s online. People communicate in ways that feel ephemeral and let their guard down commensurately, only to find that a Facebook comment can stick around forever. The upshot is the worst of both worlds: Some information sticks around when it shouldn’t, while other information vanishes when it should remain.</description></item><item><title>Labels and Quantization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:22:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</guid><description>Our obsession of applying labels to everything even whether a hot dog is a sandwhich or not &amp;ldquo;Accuracy is more useful in entry-level jobs and for novices, because as skill increases, quantification of skill becomes harder.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;This is because feedback loops which are too short for the overall system makes people focus on inappropriate intermediate goals.&amp;rdquo;
dangers of intermediate proxies? what about in machine learning? using certain quantities for metrics which are just proxies for more difficult to measure qualitative end goals Applicable to feedback-loops &amp;ldquo;Focusing on tight feedback also leads to getting stuck in local maxima.</description></item><item><title>$whoami</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/whoami/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 14:43:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/whoami/</guid><description>when I hop on a call with new people and they ask me to give a short intro about myself, I never know what to say. Surely, I&amp;rsquo;ve done something of note that would be relevant to the conversation? Yeah sure, maybe introductions are hard , but I also realized I don&amp;rsquo;t have a cohesive and self-consistent understanding of who I am or what I stand for.
I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to, but I think it&amp;rsquo;ll give me a better handle on being able to pare down responsibilities and reclaim time to just rediscover what I love doing.</description></item><item><title>Value Setting</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/value-setting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 13:31:11 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/value-setting/</guid><description>Took on a large number of commitments in the past year, not everything was something I enjoyed. Been thinking about what makes work enjoyable and
Ask yourself, and listen closely to your answer: “What do I like about this world? What pains me about this world?” Spend time developing your taste for what is beautiful, as well as your sensitivity to what is discordant, unjust, ugly, wrong.
https://thesephist.com/posts/play/
https://paukowee.wordpress.com/2021/03/06/values-setting/
Maybe a part of the exploit-explore curve</description></item><item><title>Hackathons</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/hackathons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:01:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/hackathons/</guid><description>Full Post Design Justice hackathons becoming very corporate traces the cooptation of hacker culture by neoliberalism what is neoliberalism -&amp;gt; basically let the market decide everything &amp;ldquo;For example, consider the transformation of agriculture from Indigenous knowledge of small-scale planting, harvesting, and land-management techniques to modern agribusiness with monocultures, pesticides, fertilizers, and roboticized megafarms&amp;rdquo; hackerspaces were described as originally being &amp;ldquo;third spaces&amp;rdquo; outside of the logic of both the communist state and the capitalist market &amp;ldquo;at the same time, without intentional intervention, these spaces find it very difficult to fulfill even their own liberal democratic rhetoric, because they end up dominated by white cis men and by middle-class people with free time and disposable income&amp;rdquo; [hackathons] are understood by corporate managers as potentially effectives ways to identify new talent, and therefore as a possible mechanism in the tech sector hiring pipeline hackathons provide excellent opportunities for the extraction of free labour the assumption that a &amp;ldquo;hackathon for good&amp;rdquo; will be successful if it produces a new app the can help &amp;ldquo;solve a social problem runs deep&amp;rdquo; they nearly always focus on problems and rarely build on existing community assets; and people think hackathons can do things that they usually can&amp;rsquo;t, such as solve big or even little problems, create new products overnight, or &amp;lsquo;level the playing field&amp;rsquo; of innovation through meritocracy urban design and urban planning &amp;ldquo;through such initiatives, city administrators signal that the public is invited to participate in decisionmaking on an ongoing basis, not only at the ballot box every few years&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; in response to city government being more transparent, more administrative data being made available to the public, and administrators actively seeking ideas from engaged publics about how to improve government services and city resident&amp;rsquo;s quality of life neoliberal, technocentric ideas about the city as a machine or as a software system waiting to be optimized have become increasingly prominent citizens should not be reduced to users through the lens of neoliberal governmentality diversity and inclusivity broader availability of digital design and fabrication increases the opportunity for community-controlled design processes that include more diverse users and user stories, with more equitable and inclusive distribution of affordances the assumption that making sites &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; makes them inclusive, without specifically addressing race, class, gender, and/or disability dynamics, is common to many privileged design sites such hackathons [more inclusive hackathons] push hackers to reflect on why they are doing the work they do, push for the ideas and welfare of marginalized communities in the tech sphere, and do so on the terms of their wellbeing and safety for example, this means that it is important to consider food, bio beaks, accessible bathrooms that are friendly to all body types and genders, comfortable spaces to nap or relax, and decent lighting hackathon spaces cultivate a culture that marginalizes hackers with specific needs, including but not limited to women, people with disabilities, people with non-traditional backgrounds, and even individuals with specific dietary restrictions &amp;ldquo;Steer students away from the pitfalls of tech solutionism and technochauvanism&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Make all people good coders, or make all coders good people&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s true that design justice practitioners have to take care that critique does not become our primary activity; an overemphasis on testing, evaluation, and critique can indeed by ultimately disempowering&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;However if resource constraints become an excuse to avoid examining the root of the problem area, then designers will almost always end up, at best, providing Band-Aids for deep wounds and, at worst, actively serving existing power structures&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Frequent critiques of community-controlled design processes include variants of &amp;lsquo;design by committee produces mediocrity&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up with the lowest-common-denominator design!</description></item><item><title>Dewey Decimal System</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:59:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reading/</guid><description>getting back into reading Books, with some effort, can help you learn to walk, but only people can help you orient where to walk. In other (equally vague yet obvious) words, I can’t know (through books), if I don’t know what to know (through people). (quote from eva) organizing thoughts I used to think that to be a productive member of society, one just had to put their head down and try to churn out as much output as possible.</description></item><item><title>Acceleration</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:59:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</guid><description>moving fast but not breaking things
https://www.samsonzhang.com/2021/01/19/how-to-innovate-and-create-a-culture-of-innovation.html
https://www.dougengelbart.org/content/view/348/000/
A activity -&amp;gt; core business activity B activity -&amp;gt; reduce product-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality A activities (increase velocity) C activity -&amp;gt; reduce improvement-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality B activities (increase acceleration)
The DKR is a wonderful example of the kind of investment that you can start making at the C level, with modest means, that will pay dividends back as it moves up the line to the B and the A levels.</description></item></channel></rss>