<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:34:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Knowledge Distillation</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/knowledge-distillation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:34:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/knowledge-distillation/</guid><description>https://distill.pub/2017/research-debt/</description></item><item><title>Academia</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:13:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</guid><description>MS Research Session w/ Jim Pinkelman, Ph.D. Been at MS for 19 years, 11 years in Microsoft Research
Most of MS research is not necessarily driven by a technical challenge that a product group faces. Very driven by research interests of new hires.
Missions
Advance the state-of-the-art in CS Rapidly transfer technologies to Microsoft products and services Incubate disruptive technologies and new business 95% of internal research is peer-reviewed + published</description></item><item><title>Exploit Explore Problem</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/exploit-explore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:32:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/exploit-explore/</guid><description> exploit-explore tradeoff in ML hill climbing always jump to next step up → greedy search</description></item><item><title>Feedback Loops</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:32:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</guid><description>Newsletter bit
https://brianlui.dog/2020/05/10/beware-of-tight-feedback-loops/
noise in social media used to be a town square → hear what you hear radio bar model → everyone has a frequency people chose their frequency (substack model) competing on substack vs rolling your own centaur systems human feedback loops extended cognition with centaur systems</description></item><item><title>pseudonymous-web</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/pseudonymous-web/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:57:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/pseudonymous-web/</guid><description>https://qualiaspace.substack.com/p/the-future-of-social-media-is-pseudonymous
an identity-based social graph is fundamentally limited. Your Facebook identity and social graph are mere digital shadows of their physical counterparts, and little more. By attaching our real-world identities to everything we do, these platforms feel suffocating and unsafe. &amp;ldquo;In real life and on Facebook, you’re always signaling information about yourself which may not have anything to do with the context you’re in.&amp;rdquo;
The paper introduces the comparison between a crutch and a shoe.</description></item><item><title>Cities and Programming</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/cities-and-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:53:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/cities-and-programming/</guid><description>http://tomasp.net/blog/2020/cities-and-programming/
Brand argues that many great buildings achieved their greatness by gradual stepwise evolution over time. New buildings need to be designed with the expectation that they will evolve, because they usually outlive their initial use. Even if a building does not change its use (e.g. it remains the same university department), the needs of its users will change and the building will need to adapt. This should be done, for example, by making sure that changing the space layout in the building is possible without changing the structure.</description></item><item><title>Project Idea List</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/project-list/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:33:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/project-list/</guid><description>DreamCoder boolsat https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boolean_satisfiability_problem
NeuroSAT Paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1802.03685.pdf
DreamCoder Paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.08381.pdf https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qtu0aSTDE2I
themis — go-based api testing framework 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 tests:- name:&amp;#34;test 1&amp;#34;url:&amp;#34;/test/:id&amp;#34;- var1:&amp;#34;val&amp;#34;config:flags:[]benchmark:falseenv:GO_PATH:&amp;#34;/usr/local/go&amp;#34;cases:- desc:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;type:&amp;#34;EXACT&amp;#34;# [exact, contains, regex]input:&amp;#34;asdf&amp;#34;expected:&amp;#34;asdf&amp;#34; language agnostic using dockerbasical github actions for CI integration considerations? different http verbs form data mock headers test reports can actually use concurrency lmao buffered channel of tests, run x tests in parallel cross-device folder sync - sync according to gitignore - [](https://github.</description></item><item><title>attention-economy</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:27:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/attention-economy/</guid><description>attention as a commodity increasingly competitive to compete for everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention
shortening of attention spans? not sure if this is an actual thing &amp;lsquo;digital detox&amp;rsquo; people not just as the products, but as the producers of the product (data)</description></item><item><title>emergent-behaviour</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/emergent-behaviour/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:21:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/emergent-behaviour/</guid><description>How complex behaviour can arise out of seemingly simple rules
Ant simulations Mold simulations Community dynamics Interesting to think about in context of single agents in multi-agent systems How does consciousness arise?</description></item><item><title>A city is not a tree</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/city-is-not-a-tree/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 20:39:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/articles/city-is-not-a-tree/</guid><description>https://www.patternlanguage.com/archive/cityisnotatree.html
Why trees instead of graphs Both the tree and the semilattice are ways of thinking about how a large collection of many small systems goes to make up a large and complex system. More generally, they are both names for structures of sets.
For the human mind, the tree is the easiest vehicle for complex thoughts. But the city is not, cannot and must not be a tree. The city is a receptacle for life.</description></item><item><title>Building in Public</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;He who works with the door open gets all kinds of interruptions, but he also occasionally gets clues as to what the world is and what might be important.&amp;rdquo; — richard hamming
https://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/YouAndYourResearch.html
invite distractions but get a better sense of the world</description></item><item><title>Ephemereal Content</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/ephemereal-content/</guid><description> moving towards live ephemerality pandemic accelerated blending of async and sycn convos</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</guid><description>What is infrastructure even? tbh idk
things that use infrastructure or infrastructure in the beginning not much of a distinction first tech → language how did language arise? evolve with each other? language as infrastructure for thought at a certain complexity level, combinatorial explosion of complexity does it grows as emergent behaviour? is any infrastructure ever new? is everything derivative? is thought ever new?</description></item><item><title>Climate Ai</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/climate-ai/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:06:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/climate-ai/</guid><description>how could we try to improve the processes/tools that we use to protect our biodiversity and respond quickly enough to have a chance 4 focus areas agriculture water biodiversity climate change oceanmind → uses AI to track fishing boats and identify suspicious behaviour (illegal fishing for example) wildbook → citizen science fingerprinting for animals using AI (aggregating social feeds from the public) e.g. post an image of a new animal and if its new, alert scientists etc.</description></item><item><title>Social Graphs</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</guid><description>social graph → who&amp;rsquo;s connected to who interest graph → online representations of interests constructing interest graphs from social graphs traditional social media apps like facebook/ig constructing social graphs from interest graphs more &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; apps like tiktok social graph as infrastructure? should we make one centralized social structure and platforms can then build platforms off of that social graph? china does this well focus on being end product rather than infrastructure layer that others build on top of &amp;ldquo;a platform is when the economic value of everybody that uses it exceeds the value of the company that creates it.</description></item><item><title>Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</guid><description>a people-centric smart city for racial justice cities are the backbone and hope of social change
either great benefit but also digital cages of surveillance and control
what is the role of cities in the post-pandemic phase?
laboratories for democratic and sustainable innovations smart, equitable, democratic cities tech has market AND social power
9T market cap, more than the entirety of european stock market IMPORTANT QUESTIONS</description></item><item><title>Mindstorms</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/mindstorms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/mindstorms/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;As children construct things in the world, they construct new ideas and theories in their minds, which motivates them to construct new things in the world, and on and on.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Seymour saw the computer not just as a problem-solving tool but as an expressive medium. He believed that learning to program was analogous to learning to write, providing children with new ways of organizing and expressing their ideas.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I never met anyone who was, at once, so playful and so serious about ideas.</description></item><item><title>From Countculture to Cyberculture</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/fctc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/fctc/</guid><description>Reboot Discussion How did this book start? Why and how did computers go from emblems of cold war state to tools of personal liberation? A bunch of folks like Steward Brand, Kevin Kelly, etc. (inner circle included people from the 60s to the 90s) having a person who he could follow across these generations was extremely helpful What is cybernetics? Different between social networking, computer networking, etc.
Another definition: computationalization of human processes</description></item><item><title>Design Justice</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/design-justice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:58:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/books/design-justice/</guid><description>Quotes Defining Design Justice How larger systems &amp;ndash; including norms, values, and and assumptions &amp;ndash; are encoded in and reproduced through the design of sciotechnical systems. (artifacts have politics)
Design justice rethinks design processes, centers people who are normally marginalized by design, and uses collaborative, creative practices to address the deepest challenges our communities face
Design justice is a framework for analysis of how design distributes benefits and burdges between various groups of people.</description></item><item><title>Introductions</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/introductions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 19:47:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/introductions/</guid><description>idolization
&amp;ldquo;You implicitly invalidate any struggles they have, and eschew their private life. Your praise becomes so diluted that it’s meaningless, just another reflex or polite gesture. And, god forbid they ever deviate from this god-like persona that you’ve created for them.&amp;rdquo; feels like there is rarely any space to be vulnerable bandwidth of communication mediums
6 word story → baby shoes for sale, never worn creativity in interpretation low bandwidth mediums require interpretation requires human interpretation if its good, we refer to it as creativity if its bad, we just call it heuristics why i can never do good introductions</description></item><item><title>Catch-22</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 11:28:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/catch22/</guid><description>If a pilot is deemed insane, they don&amp;rsquo;t have to fly. To be deemed insane, a pilot must request to be evaluated. If a pilot requests to be evaluated, this demonstrates that he must be sane. Therefore, no pilot can ever be deemed insane, and no pilot can get out of flying. paradoxical sitauation -&amp;gt; catch-22
no way to win double bind -&amp;gt; a psychological predicament in which a person receives from a single source conflicting messages that allow no appropriate response to be made</description></item><item><title>Search or be found</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 21:46:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</guid><description>the search box versus the feed intentional browsing vs being served by an algorithm
&amp;ldquo;I realized that the experience of research is exactly opposite to the way I usually often encounter information online. When you research a subject, you make a series of important decisions, not least what it is you want to research, and you make a commitment to spend time finding information that doesn’t immediately present itself. You seek out different sources that you understand may be biased for various reasons.</description></item><item><title>Digital Permanence</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/digital-permanence/</guid><description>Once you share something, you can&amp;rsquo;t unshare it, internet feels intractable
episode #172 - ryan schiller: librex and the free exchange of ideas on college campuses
silencing of ideas people go to colleges not to just read textbooks but to talk to professors who&amp;rsquo;ve studied it deeply and get their opinions on it but what happens when those professors feel like their can&amp;rsquo;t express their opinions? what happens when a student is offended by that opinion and the professor is at risk of losing their job?</description></item><item><title>Labels and Quantization</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 22:22:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/labels-and-quantization/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Accuracy is more useful in entry-level jobs and for novices, because as skill increases, quantification of skill becomes harder.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;This is because feedback loops which are too short for the overall system makes people focus on inappropriate intermediate goals.&amp;rdquo;
dangers of intermediate proxies? what about in machine learning? using certain quantities for metrics which are just proxies for more difficult to measure qualitative end goals &amp;ldquo;Focusing on tight feedback also leads to getting stuck in local maxima.</description></item><item><title>$whoami</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/whoami/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 14:43:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/whoami/</guid><description>when I hop on a call with new people and they ask me to give a short intro about myself, I never know what to say. Surely, I&amp;rsquo;ve done something of note that would be relevant to the conversation? Yeah sure, maybe introductions are hard, but I also realized I don&amp;rsquo;t have a cohesive and self-consistent understanding of who I am or what I stand for.
I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to, but I think it&amp;rsquo;ll give me a better handle on being able to pare down responsibilities and reclaim time to just rediscover what I love doing.</description></item><item><title>Value Setting</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/value-setting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 13:31:11 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/value-setting/</guid><description>Took on a large number of commitments in the past year, not everything was something I enjoyed. Been thinking about what makes work enjoyable and
https://thesephist.com/posts/play/ https://paukowee.wordpress.com/2021/03/06/values-setting/
Maybe a part of the exploit-explore curve
What type of work I don&amp;rsquo;t like doing could&amp;rsquo;ve spent that time doing other stuff didnt feel intellectual stimulating too much context switching What I love doing learn cool new stuff solve problems SHIP STUFF amazing community independence, ability to lead Must haves intellectually challenging does the work challenge how I think?</description></item><item><title>Reinventing Hackathons</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reinventing-hackathons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:01:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reinventing-hackathons/</guid><description>What first comes to your head when you think of the word &amp;lsquo;hackathon&amp;rsquo;? Is it a 24-hour long, no-sleep, caffeine-fueled, build-fest in a big sweaty gym?
As someone who first got their footing in computer science through hackathons, it pains me to see that this is the rep that hackathons have slowly gotten over time. By setting a precedence of requiring hackers to already have insane amounts of pre-requisite knowledge and to stay up the entire event, it discourages new hackers — the very original target audience — from attending.</description></item><item><title>Intersection of Philosophy St. and CS Blvd.</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/bitter-lesson/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:00:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/bitter-lesson/</guid><description>the bitter lesson → http://www.incompleteideas.net/IncIdeas/BitterLesson.html
a bitter lesson reframing data? speech data → audio features / mfcc inadvertently taking away the ability to make new insights based of restrictions how do we explore more of the solution space feedforward → linear relationships sigmoid → non-linear what other solution spaces are we missing constraining solution space with human heuristics</description></item><item><title>Dewey Decimal System</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:59:49 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/reading/</guid><description>getting back into reading Books, with some effort, can help you learn to walk, but only people can help you orient where to walk. In other (equally vague yet obvious) words, I can’t know (through books), if I don’t know what to know (through people). (quote from eva) organizing thoughts I used to think that to be a productive member of society, one just had to put their head down and try to churn out as much output as possible.</description></item><item><title>Acceleration</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:59:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</guid><description>moving fast but not breaking things
https://www.samsonzhang.com/2021/01/19/how-to-innovate-and-create-a-culture-of-innovation.html
https://www.dougengelbart.org/content/view/348/000/
A activity -&amp;gt; core business activity B activity -&amp;gt; reduce product-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality A activities (increase velocity) C activity -&amp;gt; reduce improvement-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality B activities (increase acceleration)
The DKR is a wonderful example of the kind of investment that you can start making at the C level, with modest means, that will pay dividends back as it moves up the line to the B and the A levels.</description></item><item><title>On GPT-3</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/gpt-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/gpt-3/</guid><description>what is gpt-3 GPT-3 is a language model that generates impressive outputs across a variety of domains, despite not being trained on any particular domain. GPT-3 generates text by predicting the next word based on what it’s seen before. The model was trained on a very large amount of text data: hundreds of billions of words from the internet and books.
a really good autocomplete
size: 175b parameters (previous SOTA was 17b)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</guid><description>Ingroup/outgroup biases get social status points we will choose to identify with whatever in-group will immediately benefit us the most why soririties + frats are successful → sunk cost falacy amount of boundaries required → well organized events vs serendipitous interactions do serendipitous interactions only come from ephemereal-content? Community Governance bottom-up emergent properties vs top-down governance homeostasis of communities mix of internal and external influence secluded vs public labels-and-quantization conforming to labels self-fulfilling prophecies sanctity of natural interactions monetizing human interaction (ondeck) how do we screen for value alignment?</description></item></channel></rss>