<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHIL321A on jzhao.xyz</title>
    <link>https://jzhao.xyz/tags/PHIL321A/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PHIL321A on jzhao.xyz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/tags/PHIL321A/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decisions under risk (DUR)</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decisions-under-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decisions-under-risk/</guid>
      <description>Decision rules when the probability of each outcome is known.
Requires an interval scale
When evaluating, we often need to quantify what outcomes are more [[thoughts/value|valuable]] than others</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precautionary Principle (PP)</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Precautionary-Principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Precautionary-Principle/</guid>
      <description>Ordinary scenarios: maximize expected utility (EU Max) Precautionary scenarios: avoid catastrophic harm (Precautionary Principle)  Tripod Framework Manson&amp;rsquo;s Framework for when to use the precautionary principle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisions under ignorance (DUI)</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decisions-under-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decisions-under-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>Decision rules when the agent is ignorant of all probabilities
Background Points  No information about probabilities A value function on outcomes a&amp;amp;s where a is an act and s is a state Most of the rules respect dominance  Rules  Dominance  Weak Dominance: act $a$ is as good or better than $b$ for each possible state and there is at least one state where it is strictly better Strong Dominance: act $a$ is strictly better than $b$ for all possible states Principle:  Avoid dominated acts and prefer dominant acts Can only use dominance principle if states are independent of acts Gold standard, use this whenever possible     Maximin/Leximin  Find the minimum value of each act Choose the act with the least bad worst-case outcome Note: can violate dominance if there are rows with the same minimum Leximin can help resolves ties by removing the minimum value in case of ties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision theory</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decision-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Decision-theory/</guid>
      <description>Choices by one agent in which background conditions are independent of what other agents are doing. We usually represent these decisions with a decision matrix or decision table</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary game theory</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Evolutionary-game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/Evolutionary-game-theory/</guid>
      <description>Focuses on the dynamics of strategy change by agents over time.
Evolutionary game theory has helped to explain the basis of altruistic behaviours in Darwinian evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Theory</title>
      <link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 10:18:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/game-theory/</guid>
      <description>Induction, Decision, and Game Theory Course notes on PHIL321A with Paul Bartha
 Philosophical underpinnings of rational decision making
 Covers</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
