<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 14:57:51 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Framing and Context Collapse</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/framing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 14:57:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/framing/</guid><description>The content I throw on Twitter is not something I would readily post on LinkedIn. I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t post LinkedIn-style business content to my Facebook timeline. To an extent, my social presence across these platforms is incongruent. The core tenet is that different apps curate different types of communities and thus social contexts. As a result, we try to separate these contexts in the best way we know how to: by acting differently, and that&amp;rsquo;s ok.</description></item><item><title>Rewriting ctrl-v using Next.js</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/ctrlv-next/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 16:55:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/ctrlv-next/</guid><description>Ever since I released ctrl-v, friends from HackClub have kept bugging me about switching my current React code over to use Next.js. I wanted to see what all the fuss was about, so I finally set aside some time this weekend to rewrite the frontend using Next.js and deployed it on Vercel instead of Firebase Hosting. I thought it would take the whole weekend, but I managed to go from zero knowledge about Next.</description></item><item><title>A case for funding Open Source</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/paid-oss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 12:03:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/paid-oss/</guid><description>Making of Open Source software I’ve recently made my way through Working in Public: The Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software by Nadia Eghbal. Not only does it have some absolutely stunning cover art, it also touches on some thoughts that have been marinating in my head about the intersection of open source and funding. So much so, that I’ve started experiencing the Baader-Meinhof effect, seeing something to do with open source and funding everywhere I look in tweets, conversations, and blogs.</description></item><item><title>Digital Gardening</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/digital-gardening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/digital-gardening/</guid><description>The first image that comes to my head when I hear the word &amp;lsquo;gardening&amp;rsquo; is of a small plot with some leafy greens sprouting their heads from an earthy bed. A gardener tenderly shovels and removes unwanted weeds and pours water to nourish the plants he wants to grow. He takes care to make sure the soil isn&amp;rsquo;t too wet and that each plant has ample space to grow. When the time comes, he harvests each fruit and vegetable and makes sure to plant seeds so that he can repeat the process anew in a few weeks time.</description></item><item><title>2020: An Imperfect Palindrome</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 13:43:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/2020/</guid><description>A year of &amp;lsquo;almosts&amp;rsquo; 2020 is:
about 9.5 times longer than a Rick Roll in seconds about 54 times longer than the number of minutes I listened to Spotify this year about how many contributions I made on GitHub this year roughly the amount of pages I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year almost a palindrome Now there&amp;rsquo;s nothing super fascinating about almost-palindromes but it is also very fitting given the number of &amp;lsquo;almosts&amp;rsquo; in my year.</description></item><item><title>Collaborative Thinking</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 13:44:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading 21 Lessons for the 21st Century written by none other than Yuval Noah Harari, and have been enjoying the book. Its approach to weaving together insights from a vast number of disciplines to create something novel is extremely refreshing. I just read a section on learning, the knowledge illusion, and collaborative thinking and wanted to share some of my thoughts that have been bouncing around and marinating for a few days as well as some learnings that I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to my own life.</description></item><item><title>Machines and Intelligence</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/ai-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:17:37 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/ai-systems/</guid><description>This blog post is adapted from a term paper I wrote for PHIL250: Minds and Machines at UBC. I hope you enjoy the post and learn as much as I did in writing it!
Introduction Historically, development of AI has taken a very specific approach — systems that represent the world through symbols and manipulate those tokens in a systematic way to arrive at a result. This type of AI was coined Good Old-Fashioned AI (GOFAI) by John Haugeland1.</description></item><item><title>On AI’s ‘Bias Bug’</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 16:27:50 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/bias-bug/</guid><description>This blog post was originally intended to be a TED Talk given at TEDxRedmond but I unfortunately was never accepted. However, I did learn a lot in the process of writing it, and I hope you get some value out of it even its presented through just text.
Hey Google Take a picture in 5 seconds. Say cheese!
See that? This is just one of many examples of where AI is becoming a larger part of what we accept as normal.</description></item><item><title>A Failure Resume</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 14:02:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/a-failure-resume/</guid><description>Imposter Syndrome has been hitting really hard lately. Sometimes, it makes me feel like I don&amp;rsquo;t deserve a lot of my current accomplishments and that I need to work even harder just to feel like I deserve what I have right now. I came across the concept of a failure resume1 a while ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a list of things that didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly go according to plan, and the lessons learned.</description></item><item><title>Docker Explained</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:14:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/docker/</guid><description>Content from my own &amp;lsquo;Docker Explained&amp;rsquo; repo. Check out the repository for example code!
Introduction What is Docker? Docker is a tool that makes it really easy to package applications into self-sustaining &amp;lsquo;containers&amp;rsquo;.
What are containers? Containers, as their name suggests, contain things. In the case of Docker, these contain all the parts the application needs to run, everything from libraries and dependencies to the actual source code.
Why containers? Containerization means that everything to do with your application stays inside the container.</description></item><item><title>reflect: NLP Model Explained</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/reflect/</guid><description>How do we tell that this is a “valid” intent?
A (not so) brief exploration of how we tackle classifying intents in reflect. Part 1 will touch on defining the problem we’re trying to solve, the data we have, and how we pre-processed it. Part 2 will focus on the architecture of the model we built, how well it does, and thoughts on improving it for the future.
The problem Classifying intents is at the core of reflect.</description></item><item><title>Interning at Hootsuite in Highschool</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/hootsuite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 08:51:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/hootsuite/</guid><description>(with insights from Calvin and Hobbes)
Since I’ve started at Hootsuite, I have
added and/or changed 6223 lines of code in 16 different repos
closed 24 tickets
made 4 new Slack emotes
listened to almost 10,000 minutes of lofi
had 1 amazing summer at Hootsuite
Including the amount of money I’ve spent on lunch this past summer, everything has been so much more than I expected it to be.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/hackathons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/hackathons/</guid><description>title: &amp;ldquo;Hackathons&amp;rdquo; date: 2021-07-01T13:36:58-04:00 draft: true Personal Experience What first comes to your head when you think of the word &amp;lsquo;hackathon&amp;rsquo;? Is it a 24-hour long, no-sleep, caffeine-fueled, build-fest in a big sweaty gym?
As someone who first got their footing in computer science through hackathons, it pains me to see that this is the rep that hackathons have slowly gotten over time. By setting a precedence of requiring hackers to already have insane amounts of pre-requisite knowledge and to stay up the entire event, it discourages new hackers — the very original target audience — from attending.</description></item></channel></rss>