<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tocs on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/</link><description>Recent content in Tocs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 15:38:31 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/toc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Human Computer Interaction (HCI)</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/hci/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 15:38:31 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/hci/</guid><description>Better HCI is better empathy
What even is HCI?
The human-machine joint performance of tasks Human-computer or human-human communication mediated by computers Many a clever invention has been termed ‘before its time’ because the inventor did not see how to build a transition from what was known and in use to what was new.
3 main goals of HCI
Designing Implementing Evaluating As designers, we are defining systems, and implementing the structures that create culture.</description></item><item><title>Informatics</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/informatics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 14:42:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/informatics/</guid><description>Information Science: the world of recorded information produced by human agency. The study of how humans produce, seek, store, retrieve, and use information.
Information Praxis Organizing Systems Collections Intentional Arrangement Infrastructure Black Box Search Information Behaviour Resource Interaction Transparency Bias</description></item><item><title>Web3</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/web3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 17:13:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/web3/</guid><description>While crypto protocols operate as open networks, do they truly enact a public if solely comprised of private capital?
Crypto systems are interesting, they are &amp;ldquo;decentralized, jurisdictionless entities that exist entirely in cyberspace, maintained by a combination of cryptography, economics and social consensus &amp;rdquo;
The cyberpunkspirit: the basic property of which adverserial conflict continues to heavily favour the defender. It should be much more expensive to destroy or disrupt than they are to use and maintain &amp;ndash; Vitalkik Buterin Index Blockchain Decentralization Public Goods DAOs Quadratic Funding Proof of stake Proof of work Consensus Play Notes on Kernel curriculum: Kernel Web History https://ethereum.</description></item><item><title>Technical</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:29:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</guid><description>Projects Project List ctrl-v reflect Concepts Docker Explained React in 30min Computer Vision Article List AI CLIP and DALL-E On the Dangers of Stochastic Parrots Visualizing Multimodal neurons DreamCoder Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) Language Models are Open Knowledge Graphs Just Ask for Generalization Tooling GitHub&amp;rsquo;s move to CodeSpaces Infra Uganda&amp;rsquo;s January 13, 2021 Internet Shut Down Notion Postgres Sharding Misc Computational Metaphors in Documentation</description></item><item><title>Tech and Society</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:06:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</guid><description>Quandaries Attention Economy Catch 22 Software and Politics Funding and Maintenance Creation vs Maintenance Hackathons Paid Open Source Funding A new DARPA AI/ML Bias Bug Data Distributions Labels and Quantization Explainability Building &amp;amp; Maintaining Virtual Worlds Digital Permanence Ephemereal Content Web3 Fault Tolerance Virtual Worlds Tragedy of the Commons</description></item><item><title>Communities and Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:05:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</guid><description> Communities Infrastructure Social Graphs Urban Planning Collaborative Thinking Group Limits Digital Commons</description></item><item><title>Personal</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</guid><description>Personal Exploit-explore Introductions Reading Value Setting $whoami 2020 A Failure Resume Hootsuite Optionality A Failure Resume Mindfulness Rationality Newsletters issue-0 issue-1 issue-2 issue-3 issue-4 issue-5</description></item><item><title>Cognitive Sciences</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</guid><description>Epistemology and Ways of Knowing Frame Problem Intelligence Language of Thought Meaning and Semantics Representation Truth Virtual and Real Worlds Embedded AI Extended Mind The Mind Body Problem Virtual Worlds Qualia Design of Artificial Intelligence Definition of Life Machine Learning Telerobotics Mind Design Emergent Behaviour Consciousness Multiple Realization of Intelligence Computability Systems Downward Causation Supervenience Symbolic Systems</description></item><item><title>Education and Epistemology</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</guid><description>Knowledge Acquisition Acceleration Feedback Loops Search or be Found Learning Knowledge Sharing Digital Gardening Building In Public Academia Research Debt Knowledge Distillation Framing Teaching Interaction Design Beyond Touch and the Screen Workflows</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:16:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</guid><description>Notes on my favourite articles and books .
Books From Counterculture to Cyberculture Design Justice Mindstorms Ghost Work Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software Articles Urban Planning Cities and Programming City is Not a Tree Post-it Note City Tech and Society The Ones Who Walk From Omelas Pseudonymous Web To Live in their Utopia Unrepeatable Miracle of Silicon Valley Misc.</description></item><item><title>Table of Contents</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:23:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</guid><description>Intro A personal digital garden and organizing system for all my ramblings and thoughts. This is the index page so that the library is somewhat useful to all of you random internet strangers.
A library without an index becomes paradoxically less informative as it grows. &amp;ndash; Jorge Luis Borges
You can search my entire garden by pressing / or hitting the little search icon in the top left.</description></item></channel></rss>