<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tocs on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/</link><description>Recent content in Tocs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:29:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/toc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:29:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</guid><description>Technical ctrl-v Docker Explain reflect</description></item><item><title>Tech and Society</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:06:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</guid><description>Technology and Society Attention Economy Catch 22 Creation vs Maintenance Digital Permanence Ephemereal Content Fault Tolerance Hackathons Labels and Quantization Software and Politics Bias Bug Paid Open Source</description></item><item><title>Communities and Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:05:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</guid><description>Communities and Urban Planning Communities Infrastructure Social Graphs Urban Planning Collaborative Thinking Group Limits Digital Commons</description></item><item><title>Personal</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</guid><description>Personal exploit-explore introductions reading value-setting whoami 2020 a-failure-resume hootsuite</description></item><item><title>Cognitive Sciences</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</guid><description>Epistemology and Ways of Knowing Frame Problem Intelligence Language of Thought Meaning and Semantics Symbolic Systems Representation Virtual and Real Worlds Embedded AI Extended Mind The Mind Body Problem Virtual Worlds Design of Artificial Intelligence Definition of Life Machine Learning Telerobotics Mind Design Emergent Behaviour Multiple Realization of Intelligence</description></item><item><title>Education and Epistemology</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</guid><description>Education and Epistemology Academia Acceleration Building In Public Fault Tolerance Feedback Loops Search or be Found Digital Gardening Framing Workflows Beyond Touch and the Screen</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:16:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</guid><description>Notes on my favourite articles and books.
Books From Counterculture to Cyberculture Design Justice Mindstorms Articles Urban Planning Cities and Programming City is Not a Tree Tech and Society The Ones Who Walk From Omelas Pseudonymous Web To Live in their Utopia Misc. Knowledge Distillation On Idolization</description></item><item><title>Table of Contents</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:23:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</guid><description>Intro A personal digital garden and hub for all my ramblings and thoughts. This is the index page so that the library is somewhat useful to all of you random internet strangers.
A library without an index becomes paradoxically less informative as it grows. &amp;ndash; Jorge Luis Borges
Notes on articles and books Cognitive Sciences Education and Epistemology Technical Personal Communities and Urban Planning Tech and Society</description></item></channel></rss>