<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tocs on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/</link><description>Recent content in Tocs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:29:51 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/toc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:29:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/technical/</guid><description>Projects Project List ctrl-v reflect Concepts Docker Explained React in 30min Article List AI CLIP and DALL-E On the Dangers of Stochastic Parrots Visualizing Multimodal neurons DreamCoder Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) Language Models are Open Knowledge Graphs Tooling GitHub&amp;rsquo;s move to CodeSpaces Infra Uganda&amp;rsquo;s January 13, 2021 Internet Shut Down</description></item><item><title>Tech and Society</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:06:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/tech-and-society/</guid><description>Quandaries Attention Economy Catch 22 Software and Politics Funding and Maintenance Creation vs Maintenance Hackathons Paid Open Source Funding A new DARPA AI/ML Labels and Quantization Bias Bug Building &amp;amp; Maintaining Virtual Worlds Digital Permanence Ephemereal Content Web3 Fault Tolerance Virtual Worlds Tragedy of the Commons</description></item><item><title>Communities and Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:05:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/communities-and-urban-planning/</guid><description> Communities Infrastructure Social Graphs Urban Planning Collaborative Thinking Group Limits Digital Commons</description></item><item><title>Personal</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/personal/</guid><description>Personal exploit-explore introductions reading value-setting whoami 2020 a-failure-resume hootsuite</description></item><item><title>Cognitive Sciences</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/cognitive-sciences/</guid><description>Epistemology and Ways of Knowing Frame Problem Intelligence Language of Thought Meaning and Semantics Symbolic Systems Representation Virtual and Real Worlds Embedded AI Extended Mind The Mind Body Problem Virtual Worlds Design of Artificial Intelligence Definition of Life Machine Learning Telerobotics Mind Design Emergent Behaviour Consciousness Multiple Realization of Intelligence Computability</description></item><item><title>Education and Epistemology</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:03:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/education-and-epistemology/</guid><description>Knowledge Acquisition Acceleration Feedback Loops Search or be Found Knowledge Sharing Digital Gardening Building In Public Academia Research Debt Framing Interaction Design Beyond Touch and the Screen Workflows</description></item><item><title>Readings</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:16:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/readings/</guid><description>Notes on my favourite articles and books.
Books From Counterculture to Cyberculture Design Justice Mindstorms Ghost Work Articles Urban Planning Cities and Programming City is Not a Tree Post-it Note City Tech and Society The Ones Who Walk From Omelas Pseudonymous Web To Live in their Utopia Unrepeatable Miracle of Silicon Valley Misc.</description></item><item><title>Table of Contents</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 12:23:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/toc/directory/</guid><description>Intro A personal digital garden and hub for all my ramblings and thoughts. This is the index page so that the library is somewhat useful to all of you random internet strangers.
A library without an index becomes paradoxically less informative as it grows. &amp;ndash; Jorge Luis Borges
Notes on articles and books Cognitive Sciences Education and Epistemology Technical Personal Communities and Urban Planning Tech and Society</description></item></channel></rss>