<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>knowledge on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/tags/knowledge/</link><description>Recent content in knowledge on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:14:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/tags/knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fault Tolerance</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 15:14:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/fault-tolerance/</guid><description>Fault Tolerance How do we defend against attacks in distributed systems with no central authority?
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byzantine_fault https://lamport.azurewebsites.net/pubs/byz.pdf
Zooko&amp;rsquo;s Triangle Postulates that names of participants can have at most 2 of these 3 properties
Human-meaningful: Meaningful and memorable (low-entropy) names are provided to the users. Secure: The amount of damage a malicious entity can inflict on the system should be as low as possible. Decentralized: Names correctly resolve to their respective entities without the use of a central authority or service.</description></item><item><title>Academia</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:13:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/academia/</guid><description>Cool People/Things http://jeffclune.com/ https://www.davidlindlbauer.com/ https://www.hcii.cmu.edu/summer-research-program https://chrisharrison.net/index.php/Research/Welcome
Tunnel Vision https://www.briantimar.com/notes/mimetic/mimetic/ Graduate programs select for intensely competitive individuals with highly specific skills, often with negligible market value outside of universities. A strong desire for publications on esoteric topics is inherited from senior postdocs and professors, making tunnel vision especially acute.
Incentive Structure Academia feels more pure, more like play? More of a &amp;lsquo;constructionist&amp;rsquo; approach, freedom to ask your own questions -&amp;gt; mindstorms Thinking about how similar the incentive structures are in hackathons Can we create the energy of DARPA outside of government funding?</description></item><item><title>Feedback Loops</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:32:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/feedback-loops/</guid><description>Newsletter bit https://brianlui.dog/2020/05/10/beware-of-tight-feedback-loops/
noise in social media used to be a town square → hear what you hear radio bar model → everyone has a frequency people chose their frequency (substack model) competing on substack vs rolling your own centaur systems human feedback loops extended cognition with centaur systems Imitation https://www.briantimar.com/notes/mimetic/mimetic/ The second was a positive feedback loop that encouraged me to spend ever-increasing amounts of time on my work.</description></item><item><title>Building in Public</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/building-in-public/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;He who works with the door open gets all kinds of interruptions, but he also occasionally gets clues as to what the world is and what might be important.&amp;rdquo; — richard hamming
https://www.cs.virginia.edu/~robins/YouAndYourResearch.html invite distractions but get a better sense of the world</description></item><item><title>Search or be found</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 21:46:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/search-or-be-found/</guid><description>The search box versus the feed intentional browsing vs being served by an algorithm
Is it possible to move away from the ‘feed’-based model of browsing the social internet?
The “feed”–an archaic form of content consumption that is effectively just a direct visual manifestation of the data structure that powers it – is a medium that is effectively designed to be consumed alone. –Humphrey Obuobi
&amp;ldquo;I realized that the experience of research is exactly opposite to the way I usually often encounter information online.</description></item><item><title>Framing and Context Collapse</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/framing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 14:57:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/framing/</guid><description>The content I throw on Twitter is not something I would readily post on LinkedIn. I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t post LinkedIn-style business content to my Facebook timeline. To an extent, my social presence across these platforms is incongruent. The core tenet is that different apps curate different types of communities and thus social contexts. As a result, we try to separate these contexts in the best way we know how to: by acting differently, and that&amp;rsquo;s ok.</description></item><item><title>Acceleration</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 11:59:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/acceleration/</guid><description>moving fast but not breaking things
https://www.samsonzhang.com/2021/01/19/how-to-innovate-and-create-a-culture-of-innovation.html
https://www.dougengelbart.org/content/view/348/000/
A activity -&amp;gt; core business activity B activity -&amp;gt; reduce product-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality A activities (increase velocity) C activity -&amp;gt; reduce improvement-cycle time, make faster, smarter, higher-quality B activities (increase acceleration)
The DKR is a wonderful example of the kind of investment that you can start making at the C level, with modest means, that will pay dividends back as it moves up the line to the B and the A levels.</description></item><item><title>Digital Gardening</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/digital-gardening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/digital-gardening/</guid><description>As of 2021, this process is no longer accurate. I&amp;rsquo;ve embraced a much more networked form of note taking which I&amp;rsquo;ve written about here .
The first image that comes to my head when I hear the word &amp;lsquo;gardening&amp;rsquo; is of a small plot with some leafy greens sprouting their heads from an earthy bed. A gardener tenderly shovels and removes unwanted weeds and pours water to nourish the plants he wants to grow.</description></item></channel></rss>