<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>communities on</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/tags/communities/</link><description>Recent content in communities on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:22:10 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhao.xyz/tags/communities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Communities</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:22:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/communities/</guid><description>Types of Communities Interest-based → same interests/passions Location-based → same geographical location, place of work, etc. Vibe-based → group energy Circumstance-based → external influence, put into the same group Can we ever have fully digital commons ?
How large can communities get before they decay? Relevant: group limits Ingroup/outgroup biases get social status points we will choose to identify with whatever in-group will immediately benefit us the most why soririties + frats are successful → sunk cost falacy amount of boundaries required → well organized events vs serendipitous interactions do serendipitous interactions only come from ephemereal content ?</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 13:15:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/infrastructure/</guid><description>What is infrastructure even? which came first, the infrastructure or the applications that depend on it? things that use infrastructure or technology in the beginning not much of a distinction first tech → language how did language arise? evolve with each other? language as infrastructure for thought at a certain complexity level, combinatorial explosion of complexity does it grows as emergent behaviour ? is any infrastructure ever new?</description></item><item><title>Social Graphs</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:05:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/social-graphs/</guid><description>social graph → who&amp;rsquo;s connected to who interest graph → online representations of interests constructing interest graphs from social graphs traditional social media apps like facebook/ig constructing social graphs from interest graphs more &amp;lsquo;live&amp;rsquo; apps like tiktok social graph as infrastructure? should we make one centralized social structure and platforms can then build platforms off of that social graph? china does this well focus on being end product rather than infrastructure layer that others build on top of &amp;ldquo;a platform is when the economic value of everybody that uses it exceeds the value of the company that creates it.</description></item><item><title>Urban Planning</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:59:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/thoughts/urban-planning/</guid><description>notes from A people-centric smart city for racial justice cities are the backbone and hope of social change either great benefit but also digital cages of surveillance and control what is the role of cities in the post-pandemic phase? laboratories for democratic and sustainable innovations smart, equitable, democratic cities tech has market AND social power 9T market cap, more than the entirety of european stock market IMPORTANT QUESTIONS smart for whom?</description></item><item><title>Collaborative Thinking</title><link>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 13:44:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://jzhao.xyz/posts/collaborative-thinking/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading 21 Lessons for the 21st Century written by none other than Yuval Noah Harari, and have been enjoying the book. Its approach to weaving together insights from a vast number of disciplines to create something novel is extremely refreshing. I just read a section on learning, the knowledge illusion, and collaborative thinking and wanted to share some of my thoughts that have been bouncing around and marinating for a few days as well as some learnings that I&amp;rsquo;ve applied to my own life.</description></item></channel></rss>